<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The late great revolution in this nation argued according to Rev. 17. 16. 17., to be duely ascribed to the supreme spirit now about to move in the fulfilling all prophecy, the earnest of which is vouch-saf'd to us in this so wonderful change, in pursuance of a discourse published twelve months past, viz, The command of God to come out of Babylon : wherein is more fully proved the [now] Roman Communion is intended and that the words of God will be fulfilled concerning the present state of the papacy in its expiration, and the hatred of the whore, 1697 / by Beverley.</title>
            <author>Beverley, Thomas.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1689</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 91 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 16 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A27615</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing B2160</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R14224</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12336128</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12336128</idno>
            <idno type="VID">59786</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A27615)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 59786)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 932:23)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The late great revolution in this nation argued according to Rev. 17. 16. 17., to be duely ascribed to the supreme spirit now about to move in the fulfilling all prophecy, the earnest of which is vouch-saf'd to us in this so wonderful change, in pursuance of a discourse published twelve months past, viz, The command of God to come out of Babylon : wherein is more fully proved the [now] Roman Communion is intended and that the words of God will be fulfilled concerning the present state of the papacy in its expiration, and the hatred of the whore, 1697 / by Beverley.</title>
                  <author>Beverley, Thomas.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[8], 22 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for John Salusbury ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London?] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1689.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
                  <note>Advertisement: p. [8]</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Bible. --  N.T. --  Revelation XVII, 16-17 --  Criticism, interpretation, etc. --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Bible --  Prophecies --  Political aspects --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Prophecies.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>Geremy Carnes</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>Geremy Carnes</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:59786:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:59786:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p> THE LATE <hi>Great Revolution</hi> IN THIS NATION;</p>
            <p>Argued according to <hi>Rev.</hi> 17. 16. 17.</p>
            <p>To be duely Aſcribed to the <hi>Supreme Spirit</hi> now about to move in the Fulfilling All Prophecy; The earneſt of which is vouch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaf'd to us in this ſo wonderful Change.</p>
            <p>In purſuance of a Diſcourſe Publiſhed Twelve Months paſt, <hi>viz,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Command of God to come out of</hi> Babylon:</p>
            <p>Wherein is more fully proved the <hi>[NOW] Roman Communion</hi> is Intended, and that the Words of God will be fulfilled concerning the Preſent State of the Papacy in its Expiration, and the Hatred of the <hi>Whore,</hi> 1697.</p>
            <p>By <hi>T Beverley.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>For the Teſtimony of JES<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>S is the Spirit of Prophecy, <bibl>Revel. 19. 10.</bibl>
            </q>
            <p>Printed for <hi>John Salusbury</hi> in <hi>Cornhil,</hi> near the <hi>Royal Exchange.</hi> 1689.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:59786:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:59786:2"/>
            <head>A PREFACE TO THE READER, Upon the following DISCOURSE, ſuited to the preſent <hi>Juncture</hi> of Affairs in the World, and to the particular <hi>Signs</hi> of the <hi>Times</hi> now Emerging.</head>
            <p>THat which bore up the great Princes, and Leaders among the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants of God in Elder times, to ſuch a Tranſcendency of Action, was immediate <hi>Revelation</hi> from <hi>God; The Word of God came to them,</hi> as Chriſt ſpeaks, and ennobled them, as <hi>Gods</hi> upon <hi>Earth.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Immediate <hi>Revelation</hi> in the ſame manner bore up ſo High the <hi>Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rits</hi> of the <hi>Prophets,</hi> that they feared none of the Powers upon Earth, how great, and formidable ſoever, in delivering the <hi>Divine Meſſages,</hi> even when they threatned them with that Ruine, which they knew would moſt en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage them to Hear of.</p>
            <p>The very ſame immediate <hi>Revelation, ſtirred</hi> up the <hi>Spirits</hi> of the <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſality of the Servants of God in <hi>Prayer,</hi> and ſuitable Action, ſo that they <hi>offered themſelves willingly</hi> to the Services of their <hi>Generation,</hi> even in the Loughtieſt Atchievements, when they knew themſelves Arm'd with the Aſſurances of the Purpoſes of God to be fulfilled in thoſe Seaſons, wherein they were ſummoned to ſuch Actions.</p>
            <p>That which next to ſuch immediate <hi>Revelation</hi> would now <hi>Inſpire</hi> the Servants of God in each Station, to the higheſt Elevation, in Divine Mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſtations
<pb facs="tcp:59786:3"/> to the World, in Prayer, and Action, muſt be a Diſcovery of the <hi>Signs</hi> of the preſent Time according to ſacred <hi>Propheſie,</hi> and eſpecially that great <hi>Propheſie</hi> of the <hi>New Teſtament,</hi> which is peculiarly entitled <hi>The Revelation;</hi> Becauſe it is and ought to be in the place of immediate <hi>Reve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation</hi> to All, who <hi>Read,</hi> and <hi>Hear</hi> it, and all the Servants of Chriſt ought to Read and Hear it. For it is the <hi>Revelation,</hi> that God gave to Jeſus Chriſt to <hi>ſhew to his Servants, things that are ſhortly to come to paſs.</hi> And that ſhewing is plainly declar'd to be by their <hi>Reading,</hi> and <hi>Hearing:</hi> For it immediately follows Chriſts <hi>ſhewing,</hi> and ſignification of it by the <hi>Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtimony,</hi> and <hi>Writing</hi> of his Servant <hi>John.</hi> For he is commanded to <hi>write</hi> for after Ages; And to encourage in ſuch <hi>Reading,</hi> and <hi>Hearing,</hi> There is a Promiſe of <hi>Bleſſedneſs</hi> adjoyn'd to the <hi>Reading</hi> and <hi>Hearing.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I do not at all doubt, there is a myſtical <hi>Reading,</hi> and <hi>Hearing</hi> by the Spirit, and Power of Chriſt inſtructing and actuating his Servants, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the Principles, and Services of this very <hi>Propheſie.</hi> And that, what is now doing, and operating, in the World, and in our Nation, is accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to it, without explicite underſtanding, or attending to the Explanation of it.</p>
            <p>But yet undoubtedly, a more open, and bold Explanation is due; eſpeci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally to this <hi>Age</hi> of the <hi>Churches</hi> of Chriſt, and <hi>approach</hi> of his <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom.</hi> We ought now to be more skill'd in the <hi>Signs of the Times,</hi> than by a meer kind of <hi>Implicite Faith.</hi> And that muſt be by the Calculation of them according to this <hi>Propheſie;</hi> for the <hi>Signs</hi> of the <hi>Times</hi> are com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pounded eſpecially of the Definition of times by <hi>Propheſy,</hi> and the events de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termin'd to <hi>come to paſs</hi> in thoſe Times, and our diſcerning the <hi>Signs of the Times,</hi> is to be by a compare of <hi>Propheſie,</hi> and the product of Times, agreeable to the <hi>Propheſie,</hi> together; even as the Time of <hi>Meſſiahs com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> was deſign'd by the <hi>ſure Word</hi> of <hi>Daniels Propheſy,</hi> and <hi>Jeſus Chriſt, mighty in Word and Deed, came</hi> at the ſame Time. Now our Lord condemns the Ignorance of the <hi>Scribes, and Phariſees,</hi> and <hi>Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple,</hi> who did not <hi>diſcern the Signs</hi> of that <hi>Time,</hi> not as ſimple Ignorance, or Neſcience, but as groſs <hi>Hipocriſie,</hi> that they would not know what they might have known; and proportionably in all times, but eſpecially in theſe Times, wherein <hi>mighty Works</hi> are to <hi>ſhew forth themſelves,</hi> and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gin to <hi>ſhew forth themſelves</hi> in the downfal of the <hi>Turkiſh Tyranny,</hi> with which the Papal is to meet in ſuch degrees of Ruine, as are determin'd to be parallel in each, and in parallel Times.</p>
            <p>I moſt humbly, and earneſtly threfore Beſeech the <hi>Angels</hi> of the <hi>Reformed Churches,</hi> That they would <hi>ſearch</hi> this ſo great <hi>Propheſie</hi> of the <hi>New Teſtament,</hi> as commenſurate, as hath been ſaid to <hi>Immediate Revelation,</hi> and that they would Miniſter out of it to the <hi>Princes</hi> and <hi>Powers</hi> of the <hi>Ten Kingdoms,</hi> that have ſo long <hi>given their Power,</hi> and <hi>Kingdom</hi> to the <hi>Beaſt,</hi>
               <pb facs="tcp:59786:3"/> eſpecially to thoſe, which are already of the <hi>Reformation;</hi> For the <hi>Words of God</hi> are <hi>near to be fulfill'd,</hi> for God had ſaid, The <hi>Beaſt</hi> ſhall have <hi>Power</hi> to <hi>continue Forty two Months,</hi> and to <hi>receive great Power,</hi> and <hi>Authority</hi> from thoſe <hi>Kings,</hi> giving their <hi>Power,</hi> and their <hi>Kingdom</hi> to Him. And the <hi>Word</hi> of God was <hi>fulfill'd,</hi> ſo that their <hi>Kingdoms</hi> were en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tirely ſo <hi>given</hi> till the <hi>Reformation,</hi> when the Morning of the laſt <hi>half Day,</hi> or half <hi>Time of the forty two Months,</hi> gave Liberty to ſome of thoſe <hi>Ten Kings</hi> to reverſe, and recal the <hi>giving of their Kingdom:</hi> As Chriſt aroſe early in the <hi>Morning</hi> of his laſt <hi>third Day,</hi> and appeared to ſome of the <hi>Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtles,</hi> and <hi>Diſciples;</hi> But it was Evening, e're he met them in a Body; and thoſe, who ſaw him firſt, were Inſtrumental to prepare thoſe, who did not ſee him till the <hi>Evening:</hi> ſo thoſe <hi>Princes</hi> already of the <hi>Reformation</hi> ſhall be Inſtrumental to oblige the reſt, who have not yet renunciated to the <hi>Beaſt</hi> and the <hi>falſe Church,</hi> to do the ſame, now near the End of the laſt of the forty two Months.</p>
            <p>Let them therefore have thoſe grand excitements, and encouragements of <hi>Propheſie;</hi> undoubtedly <hi>Cyrus</hi> though a <hi>Gentile</hi> Prince was highly anima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by the Propheſies of <hi>Iſaiah</hi> and <hi>Jeremiah</hi> for the Deſtruction of <hi>Lite<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Babylon,</hi> which Propheſies we may be aſſured were expounded to Him by <hi>Daniel,</hi> ſo great a <hi>Prophet</hi> in his own Times; how much more will <hi>Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtian,</hi> and <hi>Proteſtant</hi> Princes, exalted in their Spirits, ſummon their Prow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſſe, and puiſſance for the ſervice of the <hi>Kingdom</hi> of <hi>Jeſus</hi> Chriſt to be within theſe Eight next Years <hi>proclaim'd</hi> by <hi>loud Voices</hi> from <hi>Heaven:</hi> For when the <hi>Words of God</hi> are to be <hi>fulfill'd,</hi> that the <hi>Ten Kings</hi> and their <hi>Nations,</hi> do <hi>give</hi> their <hi>Power</hi> no longer to <hi>the Beaſt;</hi> Then the <hi>Kingdom of Chriſt</hi> is <hi>proclaim'd,</hi> although his <hi>Inauguration,</hi> as we ſpeak, ſhall not be till ſeventy five Years after.</p>
            <p>If any ſhould ſay, the <hi>Propheſie</hi> is <hi>dark</hi> and not to be <hi>underſtood,</hi> and Men very diſenclin'd to believe the Explications given of it; let them conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, it is very dangerous to ſay of any <hi>Book of Scripture,</hi> with the <hi>un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>learned,</hi> we <hi>cannot read</hi> it, becauſe we are not <hi>learned,</hi> and with the <hi>learned,</hi> we cannot <hi>read</hi> it <hi>becauſe it is ſealed.</hi> If there were by the <hi>pouring</hi> out of the <hi>Spirit</hi> upon the <hi>Reformed</hi> an united endeavour to <hi>ſearch</hi> by the <hi>Books</hi> of <hi>Scripture,</hi> and other <hi>Eccleſiaſtical Records</hi> with <hi>Prayer, what,</hi> and <hi>what manner of Time,</hi> the <hi>Holy Spirit</hi> in it did <hi>ſignifie,</hi> as they have ſearch'd for the Senſe of <hi>Antiquity</hi> in ſome things of far leſs moment, or concern to the <hi>Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> what doubt can there be but that the <hi>two leaved Gates of Truth</hi> in it had <hi>open'd</hi> to them; and by their concerted Light, and Authority, Princes would be awaken'd, and perſwa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded, ſo that the <hi>great City,</hi> and its <hi>Decimal power</hi> would ſoon <hi>feel</hi> the <hi>Earthquake,</hi> and <hi>fall.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I am not at all in doubt, but that to me, <hi>leſs than the leaſt of all Saints,</hi> and the <hi>chiefeſt of Sinners,</hi> as upon the <hi>Banks</hi> of <hi>Chebar, Ulai,</hi> and <hi>Hid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dekel,</hi>
               <pb facs="tcp:59786:4"/> and as in the <hi>Iſle of Patmos,</hi> that <hi>Grace</hi> hath been vouchſaf'd upon my moſt Attentive Thought and Contemplation of this and other <hi>Propheſies of Scripture;</hi> and upon the whole Scheme of <hi>Scripture Time,</hi> that I have certainly found, That at the year <hi>ſixteen hundred ninety ſeven,</hi> Theſe great Things ſhall come to their Complement, that are to be at even Dates with the <hi>Proclamation of the Kingdom of Chriſt;</hi> That the <hi>Pollution of the Sanctuary</hi> ſhall be ſo far <hi>finiſh'd,</hi> that the <hi>meaſur'd Temple,</hi> and it's <hi>worſhippers</hi> ſealed up [within eight,] the laſt <hi>twelve hundred ſixty years</hi> ſhall be <hi>opened,</hi> and a far more excellent <hi>Church-ſtate Appear.</hi> The Miniſtrations of Truth, and Divine Worſhip much purer, as the <hi>Ark of Teſtament ſeen;</hi> and the <hi>Witneſſes</hi> Shall have come out of their <hi>Sackcloth,</hi> wherewith the ſo long <hi>Apoſtacy,</hi> together with the <hi>Turkiſh Woe,</hi> a Judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment upon that Apoſtacy, hath cover'd them.</p>
            <p>I have publiſh'd ſeveral Diſcourſes to this purpoſe, <hi>viz.</hi> A Scripture line of Time and <hi>Solomons</hi> Song adjuſted to it, and have found none, who hath thought fit to remonſtrate to them, or reſiſt the Evidence with which I have written; not becauſe I have written, but becauſe of what I have written, I may ſay, <hi>It is written.</hi> It <hi>is written</hi> in the <hi>Scripture of Truth.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Particularly the annexed Diſcourſe, I publiſh'd a year ago, and I cannot but look upon the preſent appearance of things in the World a Juſtification of it: I have obſerv'd hitherto a very wonderful progreſs of <hi>Divine Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> in the World, according to the Calculation of <hi>Propheſie</hi> I have made. I obſerve a great Preparation for the Ceſſation of the <hi>Turkiſh Woe,</hi> upon the <hi>Imperial Conſtantinople</hi> and the <hi>Greek Cities,</hi> that thoſe <hi>Candle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſticks</hi> may be Re-placed: I obſerve yet, This ſeems to wait for the <hi>Fall of the Tenth</hi> of the <hi>great City,</hi> which motion it is to attend: I have been always of the Judgment, the <hi>Reformed Churches,</hi> that lye in the Bowels of Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, whoſe <hi>Princes,</hi> and <hi>Staple Laws</hi> had not eſtabliſhed the <hi>Reformation,</hi> were in Danger of freſh <hi>Martyrdoms</hi> by the cruel Policies of the <hi>Jeſuites Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der,</hi> whoſe <hi>Arcana Imperii,</hi> or <hi>Politics,</hi> may well be ſtyl'd the <hi>depths of Sathan.</hi> I have underſtood thoſe Churches ſymbol'd by the Church of <hi>Thya<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tira,</hi> in regard of whom the <hi>Feet of Chriſt burn as in a Furnace</hi> to this day.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Nations,</hi> whoſe <hi>Princes</hi> and <hi>Laws</hi> have eſtabliſh'd the <hi>Reformati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on,</hi> I have had firm Aſſurance, could not be re-enſlav'd, under the enchant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of Reſtoring that <hi>Power to the Beaſt,</hi> which they had repeal'd from him, nor ſhould the <hi>Churches</hi> in them, except by a ſhort <hi>Hurricane,</hi> be in any danger of force. I have had the ſame Confidence with particular Relation to this Nation, and the <hi>Churches</hi> in it, and that the <hi>Soveraign Power</hi> of it ſhall be of the principal, that ſhall perfect that <hi>Revolution</hi> of the <hi>Reforma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion</hi> into it's Complement, and on that account have pray'd for the good un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtanding of our <hi>Supreams</hi> to that very end.</p>
            <p>I have compar'd ſuch <hi>Reformed Churches,</hi> and particularly this, to
<pb facs="tcp:59786:4"/> that of <hi>Sardis,</hi> eſteeming our greateſt danger to be a Security, a <hi>ſlumber</hi> in a State though ſplendid as to this World, yet ſhort of the Glory intended by Chriſt in the Advances of his <hi>Kingdom;</hi> and that thereupon, he would <hi>come upon us,</hi> and <hi>we ſhould not know</hi> at <hi>what hour he himſelf would come upon us.</hi> I find no Reaſon to change, or ſo much as to ſuſpect, but to be more and more confirm'd in theſe Sentiments.</p>
            <p>I make no more doubt, the <hi>preſent Conjuncture,</hi> is a dawn of that great Revolution, awaiting the Year <hi>ninety ſeven,</hi> next enſuing, than I doubt, whether the dawn of the day be in advance to the perfect Light; becauſe I am not upon any ſingle Conjecture, but upon the whole Conſpiration of <hi>Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>calyptical Times,</hi> compar'd with the Regiſtries of <hi>Hiſtory</hi> in the courſe of Time ſince our <hi>Lords Reſurrection,</hi> as famous, and as well known, as the <hi>Reformation</hi> from <hi>Luthers</hi> Time is known. I am not on any ſingle <hi>Line of Time,</hi> but upon the Concatenation of Times throughout <hi>Scripture,</hi> not as it is perplex'd with the Irreconcileable <hi>Chronological</hi> Controverſies, but aſſur'd by Maſſy, Sterlyn <hi>Scripture,</hi> both by compare of the <hi>Texts</hi> them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, and <hi>Scripture Reaſon,</hi> argued from them.</p>
            <p>I have only three parts of that Line <hi>to</hi> publiſh, <hi>viz.</hi> from <hi>Abraham</hi> to the <hi>go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing out of</hi> Egypt, from the <hi>going out of</hi> Egypt to <hi>Solomons beginning</hi> the <hi>Temple,</hi> and from the <hi>Temple begun</hi> to <hi>Cyrus</hi> his <hi>Decree</hi> for reſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring it, after the <hi>Babyloniſh</hi> Devaſtation. I have alſo prepar'd ſo great a Probation, that the <hi>day of Judgment,</hi> and the <hi>Reſurrection</hi> ſo generally acknowledg'd in <hi>Chriſtian Doctrine,</hi> are at the full dimenſions of Expoſition the very <hi>Milennial,</hi> or <hi>thouſand years, Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> that I think upon the comparing of <hi>Scriptures,</hi> I have vouch'd and argued, it cannot be denyed; and as a Complement of all, I have adjuſted to thoſe Illuſtrious Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures the <hi>Prayer,</hi> we ſo generally acknowledge by the Name of the <hi>Lords prayer</hi> in the Explanation of it, and proved it to be the <hi>Prayer</hi> of, and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pared for that <hi>Glorious Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> as alſo by eminent Scriptures the Lords Supper to be the Sacrament of the Kingdom.</p>
            <p>I hope by the <hi>good Hand</hi> of God towards me to be ſo aſſisted, as to make Publication of theſe with the great, and confiding Expectation; that ſince I have had ſo great cauſe to believe, no one ſees Reaſon to chaſtiſe the Diſcour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes I have publiſh'd, and that the <hi>Divine Adminiſtrations</hi> of theſe latter Times, are going on to juſtifie them, they will be ſerviceable as <hi>Go<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ds</hi> to the enquiries of greater <hi>Maſters of Aſſemblies,</hi> and their every way <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ore accep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table Reſearches into theſe things, to the greater haſtning of the <hi>Glory,</hi> and <hi>coming</hi> of our <hi>Lord Jeſus Chriſt,</hi> and the fall of <hi>his Enemies</hi> to be his <hi>Footſtool,</hi> by the earnest <hi>Prayers</hi> of his <hi>Churches,</hi> and <hi>Saints,</hi> and that in the mean time, they will be as <hi>Nails</hi> faſtning thoſe Tents, and Pavilions of <hi>Princes,</hi> who are to ſerve the <hi>King of Kings,</hi> and <hi>Lord of Lords</hi> in their Station. For I am ſure, they are <hi>given</hi> from <hi>one,</hi> even the <hi>chief Shepherd,</hi> and <hi>Biſhop of his Church, Jeſus Chriſt.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:59786:5"/>
            <p> I am not enclin'd, nor have ever had a Temptation to repreſent the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſies of Scripture as a <hi>Doctrine</hi> of <hi>Blood.</hi> I am ſenſible, what <hi>Spirit</hi> Chriſtianity is of to its greateſt Enemies. <hi>Chriſt came not to deſtroy mens lives,</hi> but to <hi>ſave them;</hi> I expect a <hi>Battel</hi> of Chriſt, that ſhall not be as of the <hi>Warriors</hi> with <hi>confuſed noiſe,</hi> and <hi>Garments rolled in Blood,</hi> but with <hi>fewel of Fire,</hi> pure and clean Holineſs, a pure <hi>Ether of</hi> Juſtice, and Righteouſneſs; for in <hi>Righteouſneſs</hi> he <hi>Judges</hi> and makes War, and that in the mean time, there ſhall be no more uſe of <hi>Inſtruments,</hi> to deſtroy, than the moſt Righteous, and juſt Conſtitutions and Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of <hi>Nations</hi> allow: For the <hi>Angels of the Vials</hi> upon the Anti-Chriſtian State are <hi>cloathed with Linnen pure,</hi> and <hi>white,</hi> and their <hi>Breaſts girded</hi> with <hi>golden Girdles,</hi> their <hi>Vials full</hi> with no other <hi>wrath</hi> than <hi>of God Almighty,</hi> Rev. 15.</p>
            <p>Yet not offering to be particularly definitive; I Avow in the general, Yet Eight years, and the <hi>Kingdoms</hi> of this <hi>World</hi> ſhall become the <hi>Kingdoms</hi> of the <hi>Lord and of his Chriſt,</hi> and <hi>Papacy</hi> and <hi>Mahometaniſm</hi> ſhall ſink down before Him, his Monarchy ſhall then begin its Succeſſion, although his <hi>glorious Inveſtiture</hi> ſhall not be till <hi>ſeventy five years</hi> after; In which time, The everlaſting Goſpel ſhall be preached by a new <hi>Miſſion</hi> equal in ſpeed, and effect to that of the <hi>Apoſtles,</hi> and more univerſal; ſymboll'd therefore by <hi>an Angel flying</hi> through <hi>the midſt of Heaven,</hi> bringing in the <hi>fulneſs of the</hi> Gentiles, and effectual to the <hi>Converſion of the</hi> Jews; upon which <hi>Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viours</hi> ſhall come upon <hi>Mount Sion,</hi> and deſtroy the whole race of <hi>Pagan, Mahometan, Anti-Chriſtian Edomites,</hi> and the <hi>Kingdom ſhall be the Lords.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="notice">
            <head>ADVERTISEMENT.</head>
            <p>IF any pleaſe to aſſiſt in the Publication of the whole Deſignation, they ſhall receive Proportionably.</p>
            <p>It conſiſts of the Scripture Line of the Kingdom drawn from the firſt Sab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bath to the thouſand Years Sabbatiſm.</p>
            <p>The Song of the Kingdom, or <hi>Solomons</hi> Prophetick Song adjuſted to it.</p>
            <p>The Doctrine of the Kingdom, or Demonſtrative proof by Scripture, the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of the thouſand Years is the Reſurrection, or Day of Judgment.</p>
            <p>The Prayer of the Kingdom, or the Lords Prayer, prov'd principally to look at that Kingdom.</p>
            <p>The Sacrament of the Kingdom, or the Supream aim of the Lords Supper, argued to be at that Kingdom.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>T. Beverley.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:59786:5"/>
            <epigraph>
               <bibl>Revel. XVII. 16, 17.</bibl>
               <q>
                  <p>And the Ten Horns thou ſaweſt upon the Beaſt, theſe ſhall hate the Whore, and ſhall make her deſolate, and naked, and ſhall eat her Fleſh, and burn her with Fire;</p>
                  <p>For God hath put into their hearts to fulfil his Will, and to agree, and to give their Kingdom unto the Beaſt, until the words of God ſhall be fulfilled.</p>
               </q>
            </epigraph>
            <p>I Have in a Diſcourſe Publiſhed Twelve Months paſt, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plain'd,<note place="margin">
                  <hi>Gods Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand to come out of</hi> Babylon.</note> and prov'd the explanation of this, and the neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bouring <hi>Propheſie,</hi> as having it's direct Aſpect on the proſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute <hi>Roman Communion</hi> by ſuch Arguments as have never been ſo much as attack'd, in a time when there was both all advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage and keenneſs againſt what ever was offered contrary to that Intereſt, how weak, or trifling ſoever it might ſeem, and it is pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bable, They would have that Diſcourſe go for ſuch.</p>
            <p>It is wonder therefore, if the Arguments would have born it, they were not at leaſt expos'd to ſcorn and laughter; but <hi>Prophetic Truth</hi> in this matter is too ſolid to be ſo faſten'd on.</p>
            <p>This <hi>Propheſie</hi> Imports the great Revolution of thoſe <hi>Ten Kings</hi> and their <hi>Kingdoms,</hi> our own and thoſe, which lie all about us, that were known for ſeveral Hundreds of Years, to have been devotely united to the <hi>Roman Catholick Church,</hi> as they delighted to Style it, and to the <hi>Papal Supremacy,</hi> as Head of it; theſe very <hi>Kings and Kingdoms</hi> ſhall hate that <hi>Adulterous Church,</hi> made In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>famous in this <hi>Propheſie</hi> by the Name of the <hi>Whore,</hi> and ſhall Treat her with the greateſt Hatred, Indignity, and Averſation; and God will <hi>ſet Judgment before them</hi> as in the Caſe of the <hi>Jewiſh</hi>
               <note place="margin">Ezek. 23.</note> 
               <hi>Aholibah,</hi> and they ſhall execute greateſt ſeverity upon it, as eating her Fleſh by Slaughter, and <hi>Burning her with Fire.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And all this they ſhall do, as is Implyed, when the <hi>words of God are fulfill'd.</hi> That is, when the time determin'd by God for the giving <hi>their Kingdom to the Beaſt</hi> is expir'd; till then they <hi>agree in</hi>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:59786:6"/> 
               <hi>one,</hi> being under an Enchantment to the <hi>Whore</hi> to <hi>give</hi> their <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms</hi> to the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> that <hi>bears her,</hi> that he might <hi>bear</hi> her with the greateſt <hi>Granduer,</hi> and <hi>State,</hi> his <hi>Head</hi> riſing up with theſe <hi>Ten Horns;</hi> Theſe <hi>Symbolical</hi> Names are given to the <hi>Papacy,</hi> and the <hi>Ten Kings</hi> for the ſtupidneſs of their <hi>Idolatry,</hi> and the Cruelty of their <hi>Perſecution.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The time God had allotted to the <hi>Beaſt</hi> was <hi>Forty two Jewiſh Months,</hi> making 1222 Years, as another <hi>Propheſie</hi> aſſures us; ſo long the <hi>Papacy</hi> was to continue from the time of this Authority, to be accounted from 475 and at the <hi>ſame hour the Ten Kings</hi> receiv<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>d their <hi>Kingdoms</hi> in Sacred Regiſter, or <hi>Propheſie,</hi> at the Ceſſation of the <hi>Roman Weſtern Empire.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This time is alſo call'd, as given to the whole <hi>Anti-chriſtian</hi>
               <note place="margin">Revel. 12.</note> 
               <hi>Apoſtacy, Time, Times,</hi> and <hi>half a Time;</hi> At the <hi>Morning</hi> of the <hi>half Time,</hi> as Chriſt aroſe on the <hi>Morning</hi> of his <hi>Third Day,</hi> Some<note place="margin">
                  <hi>Beginning</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>3<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>.</note> of thoſe <hi>Ten Kings</hi> began to <hi>hate the Whore,</hi> and Revok'd their <hi>Kingdoms</hi> from the <hi>Beaſt;</hi> This was when <hi>Luther</hi> firſt roſe up. <hi>Ann.</hi> 1517. Yet ſo great <hi>Kingdoms,</hi> as we know, <hi>France, Spain, Italy, Germany, Poland</hi> and <hi>Portugal</hi> continue their Subjection to him. In them alſo the <hi>Propheſie</hi> ſhall be accompliſhed, when the <hi>words of God</hi> ſhall have their laſt <hi>fulfilling,</hi> that will be at the Year 1697. For as each <hi>Time</hi> is Three Hundred Sixty Years; ſo proportion<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ably the <hi>half Time</hi> is one <hi>Hundred Eighty Years;</hi> Take them to begin at <hi>Luthers</hi> appearance, 1517. they neceſſarily end at 1697. the very obſervation of which gives the expectation of that Year Credence. For none can deny if <hi>Time, Times, half a Time,</hi> are equal to 1260. Years; The <hi>half Time</hi> numbers 180. None can deny the Reformation dawn'd 1517. which things joyn'd toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther make, whether we will, or no, a great <hi>Climateric</hi> of 1697. a Year of great Remarque, as the Hundred Eightieth or <hi>half Time</hi> from the <hi>Reformation,</hi> for if a part of the <hi>Ten Kings</hi> Revok'd then as in the <hi>Morning,</hi> All muſt at the Evening; For when the <hi>words</hi> of God are entirely <hi>fulfilled,</hi> this <hi>hating the Whore</hi> muſt be <hi>fulfilled</hi> alſo, and that is at the full end of the <hi>half Time</hi> 1697.</p>
            <p>Theſe things I have more fully opened and proved in that <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand out of</hi> Babylon, as alſo in the <hi>Scripture Line of Time.</hi> I only prepare for the preſent Diſcourſe by a Summary Repetition of them.</p>
            <p>My Intention now is, to Remarque upon the preſent <hi>wonderful Doing</hi> of God in this <hi>Nation,</hi> and to examin, whether it be not a loud Alarm, not only to this <hi>Nation,</hi> but to the <hi>Chriſtian World</hi> throughout. That God hath to admiration open'd to the accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſhment of this great <hi>Propheſie.</hi> And that it is ſo, I ſhall affirm by Ten ſolemn Arguments.</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:59786:6"/>
            <p> But firſt by way of premiſal. I ſay, if this be indeed a <hi>Proph<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e,</hi> a <hi>Divine Propheſie</hi> ſo ſoon to be accompliſh'd, and that the accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſhment be indeed ſet out in this wonderful change of affairs in our <hi>Nation;</hi> it is then certain, the conſideration of the <hi>Proph<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſie</hi> is more to the great purpoſe, what we are to expect, then the faireſt Train of <hi>ſecond Cauſes,</hi> the Eyes, and the <hi>Spirit of the Living Creatures</hi> in the <hi>Wheels</hi> in <hi>Ezekiels</hi> Viſion <hi>c.</hi> 1. are much more to every end and purpoſe, then the <hi>Rings</hi> of the <hi>Wheels,</hi> how High, Dreadful, and Auguſt ſoever; they are indeed more in view, make more noiſe, raiſe a greater duſt, but the Spirit does all.</p>
            <p>All <hi>Princes, States, Councils, Forces</hi> are to be valued, and Honoured in their <hi>Places;</hi> but <hi>Propheſie,</hi> or the <hi>God of Propheſie</hi> raiſes them, gives them each their Line of Action; raiſes others, when they are at the end of their Line; takes hold, and graſps it's end, and is moſt aſſured of it. All <hi>ſecond Cauſes</hi> may fail, <hi>your Fathers</hi> are <hi>dead,</hi> and the <hi>Prophets,</hi> where are they? <hi>But did not my words by the Prophets take hold.</hi> So it was in all Ages, ſo it will be now: The words of this <hi>Propheſie</hi> ſeem to lie ſtill in the <hi>Sacred Book;</hi> but God remembers them, as his word, and ſends out his <hi>Spirit,</hi> and ſtirs up the <hi>Spirits of Men</hi> according to them: We ought not therefore to <hi>deſpiſe</hi> the ſearches of <hi>Propheſie.</hi> For who<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever can find the True Canale of them, gives greater aſſurance of the Port, and Haven of all motions, then the wiſeſt <hi>Conventi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons,</hi> or moſt Potent <hi>Armies,</hi> or faireſt ſet of ſubordinate Inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments can do; From this very <hi>Propheſie</hi> ſprung out the great Action of this Year now in our Eves.</p>
            <p>I ſhall therefore purſue this Argument, keeping wholly within the <hi>P<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ophetical Sphere,</hi> touching no Civil concerns, but as naked <hi>matter of Fact</hi> for the ſervice of <hi>Propheſie.</hi>
            </p>
            <div type="arguments">
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Argument </seg>1</label> I argue firſt, That this great change of Affairs is the Divine Prologue to the accompliſhment of this <hi>Propheſie</hi> from Chriſts Condemning both <hi>Teachers,</hi> and <hi>People,</hi> when they knew not the <hi>Signs of the Time.</hi> The <hi>Signs of the Times</hi> are not only Religious, or Moral Characters, as the Holineſs of Chriſts Doct<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rine, Life, great <hi>Zeal in doing good</hi> was ſuch a ſort of <hi>Signs</hi> of the <hi>M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ſſiah</hi> that could not be abſent; and Chriſt ſays in Relation to them. <hi>And why of yo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ſelves judge you not, what is Right? viz.</hi> from the Laws of Reaſon, of Natural and Religious Conſcience, inſtead of a <hi>S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>gn f<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>om Heaven;</hi> but beſides theſe, there are the <hi>Signs of the Times, the ſure word of Propheſie</hi> gives, as <hi>Daniels</hi> Seventy Weeks gave of <hi>Meſſi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>h;</hi> With theſe His <hi>Miraculous Birth</hi> early <hi>Wiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom</hi> at <hi>Twelve Years old,</hi> great works concerted, and theſe compar'd
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:59786:7"/> could not deceive concerning <hi>Meſſiahs's</hi> times then on Earth.</p>
               <p>I preſume to ſay, I have found a <hi>Line of Time</hi> in <hi>Propheſie</hi> reach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to near as within about Eight Years of this great <hi>Propheſie ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>filled,</hi> I gave it out a Year ago. Here comes out a <hi>Providence</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore us ſo great, ſo ſtupendious, to the very purpoſe of this <hi>Propheſie,</hi> the equal of which is hardly to be found in <hi>Story,</hi> that was yet but an <hi>Embryo</hi> in the <hi>Womb</hi> of this <hi>Propheſie</hi> at that time, I made the <hi>Line</hi> Public; far off from all proſpect, no <hi>Cloud</hi> as <hi>Big</hi> as a <hi>Mans Hand</hi> to Divine by.</p>
               <p>If now one may not, if one cannot <hi>diſcern the Signs</hi> of the <hi>Times</hi> by ſuch a <hi>Conjuncture</hi> of <hi>Propheſie,</hi> and <hi>Providence,</hi> I may humbly ſay, why ſhould any one be condemn'd of <hi>Hypocriſie</hi> for not <hi>diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning</hi> thoſe <hi>Signs,</hi> when on ſo great a <hi>Configuration</hi> one may be miſtaken. Then may it be ſaid, all <hi>Signs of the Times</hi> are Fugi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive, Fallacious, and Incertain, but they are not ſo; therefore I am not miſtaken; event will juſtifie it at 97. as it hath ſo, beyond conjecture, already begun.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Argument </seg>2</label> There is but one great <hi>Phenomenon,</hi> one great ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pearance in <hi>Propheſie,</hi> that ſeems to forbid this Interpretation of the preſent glor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ous <hi>Providence;</hi> that is, that juſt before, <hi>viz. Three Years,</hi> and a <hi>half</hi> before the <hi>fall</hi> of the <hi>great City, Babylon</hi> in a <hi>My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtery,</hi> this <hi>Roman Infamous Woman;</hi> the <hi>Witneſſes</hi> muſt be kill'd<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and by the <hi>Beaſt</hi> on which ſhe <hi>Sits.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>I have Anticipated this Objection by ſhewing, it is impoſſible the <hi>Beaſt</hi> ſhould have <hi>Forty Two Moons</hi> of <hi>Years,</hi> and have that work to do at his <hi>Three laſt Years</hi> and a <hi>half,</hi> nor does the Ana<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>logy of ſo great an event agree with ſo Puſil, ſo ſmall a time. But the <hi>Three Days</hi> and a <hi>half</hi> are equal to the <hi>Three Times</hi> and a <hi>half,</hi> and both to <hi>Twelve Hundred Sixty Days;</hi> They are in the Habit of <hi>Three Days, &amp;c.</hi> only to ſhew a deep time of the <hi>Sack-cloath Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ph<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ſie</hi> in being kill'd, as there was a deep time of our <hi>Lords Death,</hi> in his not whole, but part of <hi>Three Days</hi> as I am conſcious I have abundantly made out.</p>
               <p>But further, I argue from this <hi>Providence.</hi> This <hi>Church</hi> of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> Comprehending, as God does, all his Servants; <hi>holding the Teſtimony</hi> of <hi>Jeſus,</hi> whether, what we ſtyle <hi>Eſtablish'd by Law or Proteſtant D<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ſſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nters,</hi> is a Land of Gods <hi>Witneſſes,</hi> if there be any ſuch under Heaven; if God hath then ſo reſcued them from be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in any ſenſe <hi>kill'd by the Beaſt</hi> any more, as he has; it is certain, that <hi>Propheſie</hi> of the <hi>Witneſſes</hi> cannot be in the way of this <hi>Prophe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſie</hi> of the <hi>Ten Kings hating this Whore,</hi> that it ſhould not come to paſs in it's juſt ſeaſon of 1697.</p>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:59786:7"/>
               <p> For God hath ſo Conſolidated the <hi>Nation</hi> in this reſcue, that this <hi>Kingdom</hi> of the <hi>Firſt Three</hi> among the <hi>Ten Kingdoms</hi> muſt be deſtroyed in all Human ſpeaking, e're it can be ſo ſubdued, as to <hi>beare a killing of the Witneſſes</hi> in it, ſuch as the Propheſie im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ports.</p>
               <p>Indeed ſome reſemblance there hath been of it in thoſe ſevere Proſecutions of the <hi>Proteſtant Diſſenters,</hi> the guilt of which the <hi>Church of</hi> England <hi>hath,</hi> (I pray) truely unloaded from it ſelf up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on <hi>Popiſh Cabals.</hi> Beſides <hi>Anti-chriſt</hi> hath poiz'd the weight of his Hand very notoriouſly upon the <hi>Church of</hi> England <hi>it ſelf,</hi> to try what it could do upon it. But I doubt not at all; the <hi>Bitter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs</hi> of that <hi>Death</hi> of the <hi>Witneſſes</hi> is paſt; the differences being al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways great in my eſteem betwixt the <hi>Church of Thyatyra Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants,</hi> lying in the midſt of <hi>Popiſh</hi> Laws, and Powers, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>twixt thoſe Churches whoſe Laws, and Princes have given not only a Legality, but <hi>Sardian</hi> ſplendor and ſecurity to the <hi>Refor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation,</hi> whoſe onely danger is too Deep a repoſe therein, and <hi>ſlumb<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er</hi> upon it.</p>
               <p>Indeed I have been always much aſſur'd, and God hath verified it, Each <hi>Kingdom,</hi> that repriz'd it ſelf from the <hi>Power of the Beaſt</hi> ſhall be a <hi>Proteſtant Kingdom</hi> to the very laſt; and that it could not have any Eſtabliſh'd Prince, that was not <hi>Proteſtant</hi> alſo; for God will not give back what he hath reſcued; ſo that among them the <hi>killing of the Witneſſes</hi> can have no proper place any more, I am aſſured according to Propheſie.</p>
               <p>The <hi>Proteſtant Churches</hi> in <hi>Hungary, Savoy, France</hi> have too much made good ſome ſenſes of <hi>killing</hi> the <hi>Witneſſes</hi> but under a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother <hi>Symbol</hi> in <hi>Propheſie,</hi> then of the <hi>Witneſſes</hi> ſlain, <hi>viz.</hi> the <hi>Thyatyrian Churches.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Argument. </seg>3</label> That exceeding <hi>Infatuation</hi> of <hi>Jeſuitic</hi> Councils, which are the <hi>depths of Sathan,</hi> and as the laſt ſinking Pillar of a decaying <hi>Kingdom,</hi> argue it ſo near the end, as <hi>Propheſie</hi> hath made it; when <hi>Achitophels Wiſdom</hi> is <hi>turned</hi> into <hi>fooliſhneſs,</hi> it argues a fatal ruin near. Their <hi>ſeeking</hi> to <hi>hide</hi> their <hi>Counſels deep</hi> from the <hi>Lord</hi> by the golden pretence of <hi>Liberty of Conſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ience,</hi> as if they would Cajole the <hi>Reformation;</hi> and Gods ſo great Abomination of it, and enſnating them in it ſhows, the laſt remedies, or <hi>healing Medicines</hi> of <hi>Babylon</hi> have proved vain. God hath made <hi>their turn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing things upſide down</hi> to be as the <hi>Potters Clay,</hi> that immediately receiv'd another ſhape, and mould, then they deſigned it.</p>
               <p>Now as when <hi>Haman</hi> began to fall before <hi>Mordecai,</hi> he fell apace; ſo this great defeat God hath begun to give them declares their final zuin approaching.</p>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:59786:8"/>
               <p> And indeed the <hi>Kingdom</hi> of the <hi>Beaſt</hi> hath more Years upon it. then moſt Kingdoms or Monarchies in the World have had, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept the Ancient <hi>Babylon,</hi> as deriving it from <hi>Nimrod,</hi> the <hi>beginning of</hi> whoſe <hi>Kingdom was Babel.</hi> Had not God decreed ſo long a<note place="margin">Gen. 10. 10.</note> State; In the courſe of Human Powers, it had fallen long ago, but <hi>Rome Eternal</hi> is one of it's <hi>Blaſphemies,</hi> and though it ſays, it <hi>ſhall Sit a Lady for ever,</hi> yet it's <hi>Idols</hi> have deceiv'd it; For it's <hi>Mene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>kel</hi> is e'en at the Doors. The <hi>dephth of it's</hi> ſo <hi>old Kingdom</hi> ſhall now become Dotage, therefore God hath begun the Pattern a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong us, and it ſhall go through the whole <hi>breadth</hi> of the <hi>gre<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> City.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Argument </seg>4</label> This ſudden and ſpeedy change with ſo little noiſe, with ſo little confuſion, with ſo little, or no blood is a Landſchaph or Mirror of an extraordinary intention or deſign of Providence, God ſeems to have wrought every thing by an Immediate Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence, by a <hi>coming down,</hi> he appears to have <hi>Bowed the Heavens,</hi> and to have <hi>come down;</hi> ſo, though <hi>mountains</hi> of contrary appear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ances, have <hi>flowed down at his preſence,</hi> he hath anſwer'd us by <hi>a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mazing things in righteouſneſs;</hi> he hath <hi>done things,</hi> that <hi>we looked not for,</hi> that <hi>Eye</hi> hath very ſcarcely <hi>ſeen,</hi> or <hi>ear heard,</hi> or the <hi>heart of Man conceiv'd of.</hi> All hath been, as when a <hi>Melting Fire Burneth,</hi> and things of themſelves have run into the Form, God would have them, as the <hi>Clay</hi> or <hi>Wax turns to the Scale.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Certainly, when God does ſuch things in ſo great a manner, it Portends more, than the late <hi>terrible Earthquakes in Popiſh Territo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries;</hi> God is more in this <hi>ſtill voice:</hi> Every <hi>Battel</hi> of the <hi>Warriour</hi> is with <hi>confus'd noiſe,</hi> and <hi>Garments rolled in Blood;</hi> this hath been as with <hi>Fewe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>,</hi> and <hi>burning of Fire;</hi> and it is a Preſage, that <hi>to us a Child is born, a Son is given,</hi> who ſhall within few ſpaces, <hi>take the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Eſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>y. 9.</note> 
                  <hi>on his Shoulders,</hi> and appear the <hi>Father of the World to come,</hi> his Kingdom of Righteouſneſs and Peace is <hi>near.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>It is not to be preſum'd, that all ſhall go on juſt thus, God hath done this, that he might give notice what he is about to do; and this concerted with the <hi>Prophetical Line</hi> is a great <hi>Sign of the T<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>me,</hi> and declares his <hi>Kingdom</hi> is near to be <hi>Proclaim'd;</hi> for when <hi>Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacy</hi> falls, as the laſt part of the laſt, <hi>viz.</hi> the <hi>Roman Monarchy,</hi> to which <hi>Chriſts</hi> Succeeds, his <hi>Kingdom</hi> ſhall be <hi>Proclaim'd;</hi> and he invites all to take notice of it, his <hi>Kingdom</hi> of <hi>Righteouſneſs</hi> and <hi>Peace,</hi> I ſay is near. For the <hi>Feet of Clay</hi> Crumble, and the <hi>Iron</hi> parts from them.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Argument </seg>5</label> Things ſeem ſo to be layd by God, as if the very Merits of the Cauſe betwixt the <hi>Romans,</hi> and the <hi>Proteſtant</hi> Chriſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>anity
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:59786:8"/> were to be tryed, and very natural Reaſon, if it were to be Umpire, would eaſily tell us, what the determination from Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven would be.</p>
               <p>In the beginning of the <hi>Reformation,</hi> there was a Diſpute, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther <hi>Proteſtancy</hi> ſhould have any place or Being in the World, in that which is call'd the <hi>Smalcaldic War.</hi> And God determin'd in favour of <hi>Proteſtancy;</hi> it hath not been poſſible yet to make it loſe one Nation, or <hi>Kingdom</hi> Eſtabliſh'd on <hi>Proteſtant</hi> Laws.</p>
               <p>The time is near, when the Queſtion ſhall be put, whether <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ti-chriſtianiſm</hi> ſhall have a longer State in this World, and it is very dangerous, a <hi>Critical Time</hi> for ſuch a Queſtion to be put ſo near the end of the <hi>Beaſts Moons.</hi> Every publick <hi>Watch man</hi> then ſhould be skill'd in the Time of <hi>Babylons falling,</hi> in the <hi>burden</hi> of that <hi>Dumah,</hi> that <hi>Edomitiſh Chriſtianity,</hi> or <hi>Anti chriſtianiſm;</hi> we ſhould know <hi>what of the Night, what of the Night,</hi> what the Age of<note place="margin">Iſa. 21. 9. 10. 11.</note> the <hi>Roman Moon,</hi> of that <hi>Governeſs</hi> of the <hi>Night</hi> is; what the <hi>hour</hi> of it's <hi>Night</hi> is; for the <hi>Morning cometh</hi> to the True Churches of Chriſt, and the <hi>Night</hi> the <hi>blackneſs of the Night</hi> on that <hi>Lady of the Night.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>God hath ſtirred up the Spirit of <hi>Proteſtant Princes;</hi> and it is moſt likely he will ſo Embroyl things, betwixt them and the <hi>Princes,</hi> who are yet with the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> as ſhall be ſerviceable to make an uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſal change, and all contrary <hi>Aſſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ciations</hi> ſhall be <hi>broken in peices.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>God hath given therefore, as in the beginning, a Sentence from Heaven in this <hi>Nation,</hi> and out of his great goodneſs hath herein exalted it above the other <hi>Proteſtant Nations</hi> to give a Pattern here firſt. And it cannot but be remarkable, that a Deſcendent of that great <hi>Prince of Orange,</hi> whoſe <hi>Aſſaſſination</hi> at his Death, gave him the Name of <hi>Martyr,</hi> as his great Conduct in his Life, the Honour of one of the great <hi>Captains,</hi> who were at that time with the <hi>Lamb,</hi> and with his <hi>Called</hi> and <hi>Choſen</hi> and <hi>Faithful.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Argument </seg>6</label> I doubt not at all we may ſay, <hi>Providence</hi> hath <hi>ſent</hi> that Fire upon <hi>Earth;</hi> concerning which it ſays, <hi>what will I,</hi> if it <hi>be already kindled?</hi> That is, it inſiſts no longer upon a ſeeming <hi>velleity,</hi> or as we ſpeak a <hi>willing,</hi> and <hi>woulding</hi> to have the Fire kindled, It is <hi>already kindled;</hi> It is in Act, and in Motion. It hath ſhed or Inſenſibly diſtributed it ſelf into all the veins of our <hi>Nation,</hi> and will do ſo through all the <hi>Chriſtian World,</hi> till as a <hi>Refiners Fire,</hi> it <hi>Purifie</hi> it from that <hi>Ant-ichriſtian Apoſtacy,</hi> that ſhall not be able to <hi>abide</hi> the <hi>Day of</hi> Chriſts <hi>coming;</hi> for which this <hi>Fire</hi> is to prepare: By this I underſtand the great <hi>Zeal</hi> againſt that Impure <hi>Anti-chriſtianism.</hi> And there is to be found upon
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:59786:9"/> this Zeal as it were the very Image, Seal and Impreſs of this <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſie.</hi> It here ſpread it ſelf upon all ſorts, and degrees of this <hi>Nation</hi> from the higheſt to the loweſt; what is it then but to ſay? This is one of the <hi>Ten Kingdoms,</hi> that ſhould <hi>hate</hi> the <hi>Whore,</hi> and <hi>Execute the Judgment</hi> of God upon it, that is <hi>Written,</hi> in it's due Times.</p>
               <p>And that the Soveraign of the <hi>Nation,</hi> becauſe he cannot at the preſent underſtand the Reaſon of complying with ſo great a <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſie,</hi> ſhould voluntarily retire from the Government; till he ſhall ſee, and conſider what he hath not yet duely ſeen, and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider'd. It being indeed Impoſſible according to this <hi>Propheſie,</hi> but this <hi>Proteſtant Nation</hi> muſt have a <hi>Proteſtant Head,</hi> no other can reſt upon it.</p>
               <p>Certainly this is a very Memorable fulfilling of this <hi>Propheſie,</hi> and I am moſt aſſur'd, it is for a <hi>Sign to the Lord,</hi> that ſhall not be <hi>Cut off,</hi> till the whole be <hi>fulfilled,</hi> and it ought to be ſet up for a <hi>Memorial</hi> before the <hi>Lord,</hi> as in the <hi>Temple</hi> of the <hi>Proteſtant Churches.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>I know, ſomething like it fell out in our Neighbour Kingdom, concerning <hi>Henry the Fourth,</hi> and the <hi>Great of France,</hi> Grand-father of our King, and Great Grand-father of our Prince of <hi>Orange,</hi> There was at that time in that <hi>Nation</hi> an univerſal <hi>Zeal</hi> againſt the <hi>Reformation,</hi> which they call'd <hi>Hereſie,</hi> ſo that they would by no means receive a Prince, how great ſoever his Character was, as it was indeed, as great as any Princes of his time, though there was at that time a Complex of great Princes in the World; they could not receive him how undoubted ſoever his Right according to their <hi>Salique Law:</hi> But he was under a neceſſity to forfeit his Right, to live in a perpetual War, or to change his <hi>Communion,</hi> upon what he did, Draw a Curtain in Honour to the Memory of ſo <hi>Heroick</hi> a Name.</p>
               <p>But was not this alſo a great <hi>fulfilling</hi> of this very <hi>Propheſie</hi> ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to that ſeaſon? For at that time, when ſeveral Princes had withdrawn themſelves and their <hi>Kingdoms</hi> from the <hi>Anti-chriſtian</hi> Uſurpation, if all had done ſo, how had the <hi>words</hi> of <hi>God</hi> been <hi>fulfill'd, giving the Beaſt Forty Two Months</hi> of ſuch a <hi>Decem-Princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pality</hi> or <hi>Ten Horned Power</hi> when above an Hundred Years at that time were unexpir'd? It pleaſed God to take the advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage to Revulſe ſome of them from him, to give public notice there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by, It was the <hi>Morning</hi> of the <hi>half Time,</hi> and we are even now to be admoniſh'd by it; on the other ſide ſome great Kings were to continue united to him, to ſhow the <hi>half Time</hi> was not run
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:59786:9"/> out, but the end of it to be expected for the <hi>making Deſolate,</hi> and <hi>Naked,</hi> and <hi>Judging</hi> her, that hath ſo violated the Wedlock of True Chriſtianity.</p>
               <p>In another regard alſo <hi>Propheſie</hi> was hereby <hi>fulfilled;</hi> for by that <hi>Great</hi> Henry <hi>the Fourth of</hi> France, that Famous <hi>Edict of Nants</hi> was Granted, and Confirm'd in favour of the <hi>Reformation,</hi> of which he had been ſo great a <hi>Confeſſour</hi> and <hi>Champion;</hi> that thereby, in <hi>France,</hi> as in <hi>Germany,</hi> and <hi>Poland</hi> and ſome other Countries, <hi>Churches</hi> of <hi>Thyatyra</hi> might be ſettled, lying among the <hi>Nations,</hi> where the Counſels of the <hi>Ignatian,</hi> or <hi>Jeſuits Order,</hi> ſuperadded to other Orders, juſtly eſteem'd, and call'd by <hi>Proteſtants</hi> (or as <hi>They, viz. Proteſtants ſpeak) the depths of Sathan</hi> would yet take place, according to which, ſpringing up in a juſt Seaſon for it, <hi>viz.</hi> 1528. advantages have been taken to Perſecute Chriſt in his Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants of thoſe <hi>Churches,</hi> and to cauſe his <hi>Feet</hi> to <hi>Burn,</hi> as in a <hi>Furnace,</hi> as they have done moſt dreadfully ſome time paſt in that Nation, in violation of that <hi>Edict;</hi> and as more conſtantly, where the <hi>Helliſh Inquiſition</hi> hath been always, as an <hi>Oven,</hi> or <hi>Furnace</hi> kept hot, and burning, in Countries wholly given up to the <hi>Beaſt</hi> ſtill.</p>
               <p>And thus wonderfully hath God Counterpoiz'd the State of the <hi>Beaſts Kingdom,</hi> and the <hi>Reformation,</hi> during this <hi>half Time</hi> acccor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to <hi>Propheſie,</hi> giving yet the inclining, and heavyer Scale to the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> that his <hi>words may be fulfilled,</hi> until the <hi>Beaſts Meaſure</hi> be <hi>heaped up,</hi> and <hi>running over.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Argument. </seg>6</label> That which greatly further perſuades me, the preſent <hi>Providence</hi> over theſe <hi>Nations</hi> ſhall be in order to the <hi>fulfil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling</hi> of <hi>Propheſie,</hi> is, that it ſo wonderfully <hi>Synchronizes,</hi> or keeps time with the State of the <hi>Turk<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ſh Empire.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>I have given Eighteen Months ago public Teſtimony from <hi>Propheſie,</hi> that the <hi>Tenth part of this great City</hi> ſhall <hi>fall</hi> before the <hi>Mahometan Sultany</hi> is Diſ-mounted from the <hi>Conſtantine-politan</hi> Heighths, and <hi>De-ported</hi> from the Confluence of People, as of Rivers; ſince that, two <hi>Champagnes</hi> have paſs'd full of ſuch Action, as hath exceedingly humbled the <hi>O<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>toman Mountain;</hi> and yet it ſtands, though ſhaking, and as in a trembling expectation of the <hi>fall</hi> of that <hi>Anti-chriſtianiſm,</hi> that gave the demeritorious provo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation to the Wrath, and Juſtice of God, that ſwell'd it to ſuch a loftineſs.</p>
               <p>As <hi>Rome,</hi> and <hi>Conſtantinople</hi> were ſuch <hi>Siſters</hi> in the <hi>Apoſtacy,</hi> as <hi>Aholah,</hi> and <hi>Aholibah</hi> in an <hi>Idolatrous</hi> defection from God, ſo God prepar'd for them ſo ſore a ſcourge as the <hi>Mahometan Impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſture,</hi>
                  <pb n="10" facs="tcp:59786:10"/> that ſhould both deride their Superſtition, and miſerably Affl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ct them together; It came abroad ſoon after the conteſt of thoſe <hi>Two Biſhops,</hi> both <hi>fallen Stars,</hi> for <hi>Supremacy,</hi> and <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>niverſality;</hi> wherein <hi>Rome</hi> had the fatal pre-eminence to obtain the <hi>Key</hi> of the <hi>bottomleſs Pit.</hi> Immediately broke out thoſe Judgments of that <hi>Mahometan Impoſture,</hi> which this Sacred <hi>Propheſie</hi> calls <hi>Two woes,</hi> which have layn upon them Both, from that very time, more, or leſs: Judgments prepar'd on purpoſe for the <hi>Anti chriſtian Apoſtacy,</hi> in which the <hi>Eaſtern Churches</hi> ſhar'd deep, and which is to this day too cloſely Incorporated with the remains of the Chriſtianity, that is found among them, that are indeed rather dark Mentions of, than that Excellent Doctrine it ſelf and Holy Religion of our Lord Jeſus Chriſt.</p>
               <p>As therefore this <hi>Armed</hi> and violent <hi>Impoſture</hi> ſeiz'd above Two Hundred Years ago on that <hi>Imperial City, Conſtantinople,</hi> that ſo unhappily affected to be called <hi>New Rome,</hi> and therefore hath Dru<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>k ſo deep of it's <hi>Cup,</hi> both of <hi>Sin,</hi> and <hi>Judgment,</hi> ſo it ſhall continue under that <hi>Tyranny,</hi> as a Witneſs of the more dreadful vengeance, that is to fall upon that fouler Proſtitute, <hi>Old Rome,</hi> and ſtands as a <hi>Pillar of Salt</hi> to warn it hereof.</p>
               <p>Yet, ſo that, that <hi>Grecian Acropolis</hi> is <hi>ſubjected in Hope,</hi> and waits, as the <hi>groaning Creation</hi> for the <hi>Liberty</hi> of the <hi>Sons of God,</hi> ſo for that happy Day of the <hi>fall</hi> of the <hi>Tenth</hi> of that <hi>great City,</hi> the coming of the <hi>Witneſſes</hi> out of their <hi>Sach-cloth,</hi> and their <hi>Aſcent to Glory,</hi> as it were to <hi>Heaven</hi> in a <hi>Bright Cloud:</hi> For then that <hi>Second w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e</hi> of the <hi>Turkiſh <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſurpation</hi> upon that <hi>City,</hi> and thoſe <hi>Churches</hi> ſhall <hi>paſs</hi> off from them, and ſo muſt be near.</p>
               <p>And now that God hath ſo ſuddenly ſhaken the <hi>Foundations</hi> of that <hi>Ott<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>man Empire</hi> and made it to Totter, gave me expectations; the <hi>Anti <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hriſt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>an</hi> ſhould obſerve Time, that the Provocation, and the ſcourge might paſs off together, and it is to me moſt undoubted, this <hi>R<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>v<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>lution</hi> is in Motion thereunto; nor can I ſlight the notices from Nature, as in Convulſive Fits, in the laſt Summers Earth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>q<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>akes, giving the Alarm to both theſe Tyrannies, as together, and at Times near one to another to be overturned by other kind of Earthquakes.</p>
               <p>I add, the ſpeedineſs of the Motion in the two wonderful chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges in our <hi>Nation,</hi> and in <hi>Turky</hi> ſhew; <hi>Providence</hi> is moving on thoſe <hi>Wheels,</hi> and on thoſe <hi>Wings,</hi> that it uſes in the <hi>fulfilling Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ph<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ſie,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Ezek. 1.</note> as was in <hi>Ezekiels Viſion</hi> drawn to the Life; ſo that upon th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſe two Revolutions may be Written that <hi>Prophetic</hi> Motto; <hi>I the</hi>
                  <note place="margin">E<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 chunk">
                        <desc>…</desc>
                     </gap>y. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>1. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>.</note> 
                  <hi>Lord have haſten'd them in their own Time.</hi>
               </p>
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:59786:10"/>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Argument </seg>7</label> The dreadfulneſs of the <hi>Perſecution in France<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> of ſo black, and Inhuman a Barbarity, and even Helliſh Cruelty, ſpeaks ſome great Judgment near upon that <hi>Beastianiſm,</hi> that hath the <hi>Horns of a Lamb,</hi> but the <hi>Mouth</hi> of a <hi>Dragon, viz.</hi> under the Name of a Chriſtian <hi>Hierarchy,</hi> the likeneſs of a <hi>Lyon,</hi> a <hi>Bear,</hi> and a <hi>Leopard,</hi> and on that <hi>Imperious Whoriſh Woman,</hi> that is, under the <hi>Myſtery</hi> on it's <hi>Fore head of Mother-Church,</hi> the <hi>Mother of the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bominations of the Earth,</hi> and in whom the <hi>Blood</hi> of the <hi>Saints, Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tyrs,</hi> and <hi>Prophets</hi> is to be found, whoſe Adulterous Religion is Arm'd with a Salvageneſs moſt contrary to the Natural tenderneſs of Manly Nature, and moſt eſpecially to the Laws of Chriſtianity, and yet whatever is done for the propagating it's <hi>Golden Cup</hi> of <hi>Fornication,</hi> though by the moſt Feral force, is called <hi>doing God Service.</hi> Now before the <hi>Judgment</hi> Executed upon <hi>Babylon,</hi> ſhe is to <hi>fill her Ephah,</hi> that ſhe may be <hi>Rewarded double</hi> for all, that ſhe is to do; who then can but think, that her <hi>Day</hi> is <hi>near,</hi> and that <hi>God</hi> will be a <hi>ſwift Witneſs</hi> againſt her, not for <hi>Three Tranſgreſſions or Four,</hi> but for her <hi>Seventy Times Seven Abominations?</hi>
               </p>
               <p>God does not uſe to bear <hi>long with</hi> Atrocious wickedneſſes, nor give up to ſuch <hi>un-naturalneſs,</hi> but when he is ready to <hi>take ven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gance,</hi> He allows not the wonted Truce of patience in ſuch out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rages of Blood, but <hi>riſes, now,</hi> to the <hi>Prey.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>I confeſs, this <hi>Perſecution</hi> would incline one to think, were there not deep Reaſons in <hi>Proph<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ſie</hi> to the contrary, with that ſo Zeal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous <hi>Confeſſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ur,</hi> and in great degrees <hi>Martyr Mounſieur Jurien,</hi> that the <hi>Witneſſes</hi> are <hi>Slaying,</hi> as in a <hi>Three laſt Days</hi> and <hi>half,</hi> of the 1260. and <hi>lying dead</hi> in <hi>France,</hi> as in that <hi>Street</hi> of the <hi>great City,</hi> and that when this Laſt is Scene perfectly Repreſented, <hi>the Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes ſhall riſe,</hi> and that <hi>great City, viz.</hi> it's <hi>Tenth,</hi> or <hi>Hierarchy</hi> ſhall fall from it's <hi>Tenfolded Dominion</hi> fully, and finally, and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doubtedly All this is an <hi>Epitome,</hi> or ſhort review of that <hi>Slaugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter</hi> of the <hi>Witneſſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>s,</hi> and the happy <hi>Reſurrection</hi> ſhall be in fewer Years, then that Excellent Perſon hath warily taken in, as the largeſt compaſs of time for the doing it.</p>
               <p>And I am very deſirous to believe, this <hi>French Perſecution</hi> is that laſt effort of <hi>Anti-chriſtianiſm,</hi> revealed to our great and Holy Arch biſhop <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſher,</hi> the foreſt, but ſhorteſt Ravage of the <hi>Beaſt</hi> up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the <hi>Proteſt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nt World,</hi> wherein by <hi>Sympathy</hi> every Nation ſhould bear a deep ſhare, and we particularly, ſeeing it hath pleaſed our Good and Gracious God to pull us as <hi>Brands out of the burning,</hi> and <hi>who knows but we are Deliver'd for ſuch a time as this?</hi> Even for their Deliverance alſo; and that if we <hi>altogether h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ld our peace,</hi>
                  <pb n="12" facs="tcp:59786:11"/> and think to be quiet in our own <hi>Nation, Light &amp; Deliverance</hi> ſhall <hi>ariſe to thoſe Slain Witneſſes</hi> of <hi>France</hi> from ſome other place; But <hi>our S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>n will find us out,</hi> If we <hi>forbear to deliver them that are drawn unto Death,</hi> and thoſe that are <hi>ready to be Slain; If we ſay,</hi> behold we <hi>know it not,</hi> we are not concern'd, <hi>doth not he that pondereth the heart conſider it? He that keepeth our Nation doth not he know it?</hi> And w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ll he not <hi>remember it in the Day,</hi> when he <hi>maketh Inquiſition for Blood?</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Argument </seg>8</label> There is great hope, this <hi>Revolution</hi> will be the Buoying up ſubſtantial <hi>Chriſtianity,</hi> and <hi>Proteſtancy,</hi> (which is <hi>Chriſtianity</hi> return'd to it's own Dignity, and Excellency) and that <hi>Form</hi> and <hi>Ceremony</hi> are <hi>dropping off</hi> from us, at leaſt ſo far, as it hath been matter of diſtinction, and moſt of all of difference, and di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſion, or breach of Love, and Charity.</p>
               <p>Now ſuch a S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ate Borders near upon the State of the <hi>Philadelphi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>an Church,</hi> the <hi>Church</hi> Temper'd, Cemented, United by <hi>Brother<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Love,</hi> when the <hi>Envy</hi> and <hi>Vexation</hi> one of another, on ſuch ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counts ſhall <hi>depart,</hi> and we ſhall exerciſe them no more; when this ſhall indeed be, the time of the <hi>Philadelphian Church</hi> ſhall be; Every glimps of one is the glimps of the other, and when the Time of that <hi>Church</hi> is, the Time of the <hi>Apoſtacy</hi> is expir'd: Hence there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I hope the Time of all is near.</p>
               <p>Two things moſt expreſs that State; <hi>Eſſence of Chriſtianity,</hi> and <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>niverſality.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Principles, and Conſtitutions of ſome <hi>Proteſtant Churches</hi> are too full of <hi>Ceremony, Ritu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>liſm,</hi> and <hi>Formality,</hi> theſe eſpecially, when rigorouſly preſſed to an <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>niformity</hi> are nearer to <hi>Anti-chriſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>aniſm</hi> then to true <hi>Chriſtianity, Proteſtantiſm,</hi> or to the <hi>Kingdom of Chriſt.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe when Luxuriant, and over ſpreading, when Zealouſly inſiſted upon, when Perſecutorily urg'd are then call'd the <hi>Syna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gogue of Sathan; viz.</hi> in the Church of <hi>Smyrna</hi> at the Entrance of the <hi>Ap<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ſtacy,</hi> and in the <hi>Church of Pbiladelphia,</hi> when the <hi>Apoſtacy</hi> ſhall expire; The firſt Entrances, the Avenues of <hi>Anti-chriſtianiſm</hi> were <hi>un-written</hi> obſervances; over affection to <hi>Places, Days, Forms, Rites, Titles,</hi> ſwelling beyond the <hi>Apoſtolic Simplicity,</hi> hence it came to <hi>Superſtition, Idolatry, Supremacy,</hi> this State the Holy Spirit Brands, firſt the <hi>Synagogue of Sathan,</hi> becauſe ſome were <hi>Authoritative, Juriſdictive, Excommunicative</hi> upon them; al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though not to be vouched from the word of Chriſt; &amp; though they were before the very <hi>Apoſtacy,</hi> or Church it ſelf in the <hi>Wilderneſs,</hi> before the <hi>Throne</hi> of <hi>Sathan:</hi> Again, ſuch a State of things falls
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:59786:11"/> under the ſame Brand towards the end of the <hi>Apoſtacy,</hi> near and at the very <hi>Philidelphian State,</hi> when ſome are ſticking in theſe, as if the <hi>Reformation</hi> were not to move them, but that they ought to continue for the ſake of <hi>Reverence to Antiquity,</hi> this ſeems to me a miſtake like that, but in a much greater concern, with which ſome Learned <hi>Mathematicians</hi> charge <hi>Pope Gregory</hi> the <hi>Thirteenth,</hi> his Reformation of the <hi>Calendar,</hi> He Reform'd down to the <hi>Nicene Council,</hi> but not to the <hi>Days of Julius Ceſar,</hi> by whom the Calendar was firſt Formed, on which Account even new Style is, not perfect, as to Time; ſo ſome <hi>Proteſtants</hi> would <hi>Reform</hi> down to the <hi>Four firſt General Councils;</hi> but they ought to <hi>Reform</hi> down to <hi>Chriſt,</hi> and his <hi>Apoſtles,</hi> by whom as the <hi>Author</hi> and <hi>Infallible Miniſters Chriſtianity</hi> was Originally Planted; they forget the <hi>My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtery of Iniquity Began to work</hi> even in the <hi>Apoſtles Days,</hi> and was Counter wrought by their <hi>Infallible Writings,</hi> in which all things are to be tryed, to Inſiſt upon any thing not <hi>Written</hi> there, is a Redivival of that <hi>Synagogue,</hi> when over Zealouſly affected, much more, Impos'd under the Awe of <hi>Penalties,</hi> and <hi>Excommunications,</hi> which is the <hi>Form</hi> of a <hi>Synagogue of Sathan.</hi> But with this differ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence; the <hi>Apoſtacy</hi> was in the <hi>Church of Smyrna</hi> in the <hi>Aſcen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dency,</hi> ſo it went on to a <hi>Throne of Sathan.</hi> It is now towards it's loweſt <hi>Declination,</hi> ſo the <hi>laſt Synagogue</hi> ſhall come to <hi>Worſhip at Philadelphiaes Feet,</hi> and to <hi>acknowledge,</hi> Chriſt Loves that <hi>Church.</hi> And I hope that Day is now Springing; and no ſure<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Sign of the <hi>Apoſtacy expiring.</hi> This very <hi>Synagogue Seal'd</hi> the <hi>Thunders,</hi> that had <hi>utter'd their voices</hi> at the firſt <hi>Reformation;</hi> It hath near this <hi>Hundred and Eighty Years</hi> retarded the <hi>Ki<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>gdom of Chriſt,</hi> and <hi>Shut</hi> up the <hi>Book</hi> as hid in the <hi>Bowels of Propheſie</hi> then opened, and ready to have come into Act, but when that <hi>Syna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gogue</hi> begins to acknowledge it's Error, that <hi>Kingdom</hi> is near: But on the other ſide <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>niverſality</hi> is another principle of the <hi>Philadel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phian Church;</hi> ſome <hi>Proteſtant Churches</hi> are too narrow, and Cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cumſcrib'd within their own Congr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>gations; and will not own, nor receive thoſe as the Church of Chriſt, whom Chriſt hath <hi>re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiv'd,</hi> although they even as themſelves, are among the <hi>undefiled Names of Sardis</hi> how <hi>few</hi> ſoever: They ſhould <hi>go and Learn</hi> what that <hi>meaneth, Chriſt pleaſed not himſelf:</hi> For it is <hi>Written,</hi> the <hi>re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proaches of them that reproached thee, fell upon me,</hi> that is, our very Sins, not by way of complyance, but by way of Compaſſion, union to the perſons notwithſtanding their Sins, or Infirmities; Chriſt is the Head of a <hi>Church</hi> under many remaining evils, we ſhould own our ſelves the <hi>Members</hi> of ſuch a <hi>Church;</hi> An Univer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſal
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:59786:12"/> Spirit is moſt of the Spirit of <hi>Chriſts Kingdom</hi> opening to receive the <hi>fulneſs</hi> of the <hi>Gentiles,</hi> and <hi>Jews,</hi> how much more real <hi>Chriſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans</hi> and <hi>Proteſtants;</hi> Not encloſing Auſterely our ſelves in pend up Congregations; ſo as not to unite in <hi>Spirit</hi> with all true <hi>Chriſtianity</hi> and <hi>Proteſtancy</hi> though not of our Model.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Argument </seg>9</label> It is in the place of a great Argument, that the greateſt Objection againſt the hope of ſo great a Mercy, ſo happy a <hi>Revolution</hi> as we are Diſcourſing of near us, is remov'd by this preſent Revolution, that <hi>our Eyes have ſeen, our Ears heard,</hi> and <hi>our Hands handled;</hi> that is, that all our Senſes are fully aſſur'd of; the ſins, the unworthineſs, the unpreparedneſs of the Age for ſo happy a <hi>Revolution</hi> is the great Argument againſt it.</p>
               <p>But it that could have interpos'd, we of this Nation had not re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiv'd ſo great a <hi>wonder</hi> of <hi>Providence</hi> in favour of us; I delight not to inſiſt on ſo ungrateful a part, but leave it to every one in their own ſerious Reflexions to Calculate the greatneſs of this work in mercy to us, by Ballancing all the unworthineſs, that might have oppoſed it; but when God is pleaſed thus to work; As his <hi>work</hi> is <hi>before him</hi> in his own determination to do it; ſo his <hi>reward is with him,</hi> he expects it only from himſelf; He ſecures all, that his own Wiſdom and Holineſs requires, and prevails over the remainder of unworthineſs by his own <hi>Names ſake.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And of this I take the more earneſt notice, that we may know <hi>Pr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>phetical</hi> events are like the <hi>Rain,</hi> that <hi>waits</hi> not for the <hi>Sons of Men,</hi> but having ſuch a <hi>Generation</hi> of the <hi>Juſt,</hi> of the <hi>Children of God</hi> in the World, whom <hi>Fatherly Providence</hi> hath a peculiar Eye upon, it falls on the <hi>unjuſt</hi> alſo.</p>
               <p>Yet this is to be underſtood with three Limitations.</p>
               <p n="1">1. There are yet Eight Years for a variety of diſpoſes to ſhow themſelves in, either of Mercy, or Judgment; In this Time the <hi>Carcaſes</hi> of many of the <hi>mixed Multitude</hi> may <hi>fall,</hi> as in a <hi>Wilder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ſs:</hi> There may be <hi>Wars, noiſes of War, Commotions, diſtreſs of Nations,</hi> and great <hi>p<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>plexity</hi> with many evils, that may <hi>conſume</hi> prophane, and <hi>un ref<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>rm'd</hi> Perſons, we ought not therefore to be ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>cure, or preſuming becauſe of ſo great a Mercy, nor on the other ſide be diſcourag'd at contrary appearances; For whatever wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving of things may be in this Interval, the end ſhall yet be certain, as <hi>Propheſie</hi> hath declar'd.</p>
               <p n="2">2. There will be nothing, there can be nothing more dreadful to the un-holy, to the ſleepy, and ſecure, to the Ignorant, and <hi>A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bominable,</hi> then that approach, then thoſe <hi>loud voices</hi> from <hi>Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven</hi> of the <hi>Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> when theſe things come to paſs;
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:59786:12"/> Chriſt expreſſes it in brief to all thoſe in <hi>defiled Garments</hi> in <hi>Sard<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 chunk">
                        <desc>…</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> except <hi>thou watch,</hi> I will come upon thee as a <hi>Thief,</hi> and <hi>thou ſhalt not know,</hi> at what <hi>hour I will come upon thee, bleſſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>d are they</hi> then, or even at this Time, (though it ſhall have a greater <hi>fulfilling</hi> juſt at the <hi>Seventh Vial)</hi> who <hi>watch,</hi> and <hi>keep their Garments, viz.</hi> from <hi>defilements,</hi> becauſe Chriſt comes now alſo as a <hi>Thief,</hi> and on ſuch a ſurprizal, the unprepar'd, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hrowing off their <hi>defiled Garments</hi> in haſte walk <hi>naked,</hi> and Men ſee their ſhame. The greateſt Zeal of <hi>Proteſtancy,</hi> if <hi>un-reform'd</hi> in <hi>heart</hi> and <hi>Life</hi> will be affrighted even to endleſs diſtraction, and confuſion, at this approach of Chriſt, if Men do not before <hi>watch,</hi> that is, <hi>reſolve what manner of Perſons they ought to be in all Holineſs and Godlineſs of Converſation not</hi> ſur-charg'd with Drunkenneſs, Gluttony, the cares of this Life, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="3">3. With Relation to the Grand <hi>Appearance</hi> of Chriſt, there are between the <hi>Loud Voices</hi> in <hi>Heaven,</hi> that the <hi>Kingdoms of this World</hi> are <hi>become the Kingdoms of the Lord,</hi> and <hi>of his Chriſt,</hi> between the end of <hi>Time, Times,</hi> and <hi>half a Time,</hi> which are the 1260. <hi>D.</hi> and the <hi>Kingdom</hi> it ſelf, <hi>Thirty Days</hi> for Years, making 1290. wherein the <hi>Seven Thunders</hi> ſo long <hi>ſeal'd</hi> ſhall be <hi>open'd</hi> in Seven Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſive <hi>Voices</hi> for the Reforming, the purifying, the Converting the World, the World of all ſorts of Men, that whatever remains <hi>filthy</hi> may be <hi>filthy ſtill,</hi> even forever; becauſe it <hi>would</hi> not be <hi>cleans'd,</hi> when God would have <hi>cleans'd</hi> it, which <hi>Voices</hi> we may find in their due order <hi>Revel.</hi> 14. compare the Time of Thirty Years, <hi>Dan.</hi> 12. And theſe ſhall be, before Chriſt comes to <hi>Smite the Earth with a Curſe;</hi> For immediately upon thoſe <hi>Voices</hi> come <hi>Forty Five Years</hi> of the <hi>V<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>als,</hi> making up 1335. in <hi>Daniel<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> theſe are the Execution of the <hi>Holy</hi> and <hi>pure Wrath of Almighty God</hi> without <hi>mixture</hi> of any Human Paſſions, or Ends. Then at the end of them is the <hi>Glorious Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> the <hi>New Jeru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſalem,</hi> wherein all his Saints, and Servants from firſt to laſt <hi>ſtand</hi> in their <hi>Lots,</hi> and whereinto <hi>nothing,</hi> that is <hi>defiled</hi> ſhall <hi>Enter:</hi> Thus God hath ſecured his Mercies, though vouchſaf<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>d to an Impure World now.</p>
               <p>All which conſiderations exceedingly ſtrengthen the Arguments, and remove the Objections ariſing from ſo Impure, and indiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pos'd a State of the World in General, and of this <hi>Nation</hi> in particular, for ſo Gracious Manifeſtations of God, as this <hi>Propheſie Predicts.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Argument </seg>10</label> There is one Note in this <hi>Propheſie,</hi> that gives a further glance upon the near approach of the Time, and that this <hi>Revolution</hi> looks to the very juſt Complement of the <hi>words of God</hi>
                  <pb n="16" facs="tcp:59786:13"/> 
                  <hi>to be fulfilled;</hi> And that is, that whereas the <hi>Propheſie</hi> had ſaid; The <hi>Ten Kings</hi> ſhould <hi>agree to give their Kingdom to the Beaſt,</hi> till the <hi>Words</hi> of <hi>God</hi> ſhould be <hi>fulfilled;</hi> It without any notice of their withdrawing their <hi>Kingdom</hi> from the <hi>Beaſt</hi> tells us, <hi>they ſhall hate the Wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>re.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Now it is True, Their being <hi>Drunk</hi> with the <hi>Wine</hi> of the <hi>Whores Fornication</hi> is the Reaſon of their <hi>gi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ing their Kingdom to the Beaſt</hi> that <hi>carries</hi> her, as hath been before obſerv'd, and therefore when e're they <hi>hate the Whore,</hi> they will certainly withdraw their <hi>Power</hi> from the <hi>Beaſt;</hi> But becauſe it is ſaid, <hi>they ſhall hate the Whore</hi> without any mention, how they ſhall behave themſelves to the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> and that it ſeems to be the peculiar note of the <hi>Propheſie ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>led,</hi> that they <hi>hate the Whore,</hi> it mov'd my enquiry, whether either in the firſt <hi>Reformation,</hi> or at the Time of this <hi>Revolution,</hi> there be any <hi>ſhade</hi> of any <hi>King,</hi> dividing the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> and the <hi>Whore,</hi> that is, of a Retrenchment of their <hi>Power</hi> from the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> and yet continuing their kindneſs to the <hi>Whore,</hi> that the diſtinct particular <hi>Hatred</hi> might, as I may ſay, Perpendicularly fall on the <hi>Whore,</hi> the minds of any Princes Jealous of their <hi>Power,</hi> and the Honour of their <hi>Kingdom</hi> having any ways been mov'd with an Indigna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion at the Curtalling their <hi>Power,</hi> and <hi>Kingdom</hi> by <hi>giving</hi> it to the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> and ſo have re-call'd it: For if ſuch can be found, it ſeem'd to me a great note of the <hi>fulfilling</hi> this <hi>Propheſie, viz.</hi> If the <hi>Whore</hi> was firſt ſo diſtinctly loved, that then by her ſelf ſhe might be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pos'd to Univerſal <hi>hatred</hi> afterward.</p>
               <p>And I find, that there have been ſome <hi>Specimens</hi> of it all a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>long, and in the beginning of the <hi>Reformation</hi> by out <hi>King Henry the Eighth,</hi> who retain'd his kindneſs to the <hi>Roman Catholic Church</hi> in it's Doctrine<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and Worſhip<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and veneration of it, and Monſtrous Zeal for it in all theſe, and yet remov'd the <hi>Power of the Beaſt</hi> from his <hi>Regalia</hi> in all Points; But never was there ſo Ample, and Il<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luſtrious a Repreſentation of it, as in the preſent <hi>French King,</hi> who hath ſo with his <hi>Clergy</hi> Lower'd, and even Annul'd the Power of the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> or the <hi>Pope</hi> in their <hi>Gallicane Church,</hi> and yet ſo cloſely eſpous'd the <hi>Apoſtacy</hi> of the <hi>Whore,</hi> and under the very Name of the <hi>Roman Catholic Church,</hi> and ſo In-humanly Perſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted the <hi>Reformed,</hi> as <hi>H<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>retics,</hi> as if that <hi>King</hi> would himſelf take upon him to be the <hi>Beaſt bearing that Church,</hi> and to Relieve the <hi>Pope</hi> from ſo ungentile, as well as <hi>A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ti chriſtian</hi> Office: By which he, and his Clergy have offer'd theſe great Inſtructions to the World.</p>
               <p n="1">1. That the <hi>Roman Catholick Church,</hi> as call'd, whatever hands
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:59786:13"/> the <hi>Adminiſtration</hi> of it be in, will ſhew it ſelf to be the <hi>Whore,</hi> the <hi>Mother</hi> of the <hi>Abominations</hi> of the <hi>Earth,</hi> of <hi>Superſtitions</hi> and <hi>Idola<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries,</hi> and that drinks it ſelf <hi>drunk with the Blood of the Saints,</hi> and of the <hi>Martyrs of Jeſus;</hi> and that whoever ſerves it ſhall be intox<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>icated with the <gap reason="foreign">
                     <desc>〈 in non-Latin alphabet 〉</desc>
                  </gap>, the Sting, the High Rage, and <hi>Fury</hi> of its <hi>Fornication,</hi> and ſhall enforce the ſame <hi>Cup</hi> with utmoſt Barbarity into the Hands, and Mouths of thoſe, who refuſe it.</p>
               <p n="2">2. That the diſtinction betwixt the <hi>Court of Rome,</hi> and the <hi>Church of Rome</hi> is a vain and frivolous ſhift, an <hi>Apron of Fig<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>leaves</hi> to hide the impurity and filthineſs of the <hi>Whore;</hi> for at this day in <hi>France</hi> are found, however palliated, the <hi>Sorceries, Idolatries,</hi> and <hi>Murthers</hi> of the <hi>Church of Rome,</hi> where the <hi>Court of Rome</hi> is ſo much defied. This is, as it were, on purpoſe ordered by <hi>Providence</hi> to expoſe the <hi>Whore,</hi> by her ſelf alone.</p>
               <p n="3">3. That there ſhall be as great an Inſtance, as can be, of <hi>Hating the Whore,</hi> or <hi>Church of Rome</hi> by it ſelf; and as diſtinct, as can be ſuppoſed in that cloſe Conjunction it hath with the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> and the <hi>Beaſt</hi> with it: The very abſtracted Religion of the <hi>Roman Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion</hi> ſhall be deteſted for its own ſake, without Relation to <hi>Politics,</hi> or to the Uſurpation of the <hi>Beaſt</hi> or <hi>Papacy</hi> over National Rights. And whenever this is, It is the watch word of this <hi>Prophecy,</hi> that It is near <hi>fulfilling.</hi> And becauſe things are ſo much prepared in <hi>France</hi> hereunto, It is a very great ground of Expectation, that there this great <hi>Prophecy</hi> ſhall begin to be <hi>fulfilled,</hi> above any of the Kingdoms devoted to the <hi>Beaſt</hi> and <hi>Whore</hi> as united; and that the Time is as near, as I have from this <hi>Prophecy</hi> declared, and that by ſome wonderful Hand of God, parallel to what hath been in <hi>our Nation,</hi> the Action ſhall go on there, to which there are many other <hi>Prognoſtics</hi> leading, not fit to be here recounted, where we inſiſt wholly on <hi>Prophecy</hi> and <hi>Providence</hi> compar'd.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="inferences">
               <p>I now conclude this Argumentative part with theſe brief Infe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rences.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Infer. </seg>1</label> Theſe Conſiderations of <hi>Prophecy</hi> deſigning ſo great Ends, ſhew the Vanity of ſuch Reaſonings; What is <hi>Prophecy</hi> to us, or the <hi>Ten Kings hating the Whore?</hi> If we have the Laws, and Liberties of our own <hi>Government,</hi> of which <hi>Proteſtant Religion</hi> is become ſo Eſſential a part, that we cannot have the one without the other; we have what we deſire, we meddle not with dark <hi>Propheſies</hi> beyond <hi>our Line;</hi> we conſider the Natural and Political Cauſes of theſe Things, which lye ſo plain before us, and meddle not beyond them.</p>
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:59786:14"/>
               <p> But, <hi>be not deceived, God is not mocked,</hi> nor can be juſtled out of his Purpoſes by ſuch low Deſignments of ours; He hath a <hi>Wheel</hi> within every <hi>Wheel</hi> of ours, which being acted by his Supreme <hi>Spirit,</hi> ſhall move on to its Ends, and carry all our <hi>Wheeles</hi> thi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther with it ſelf; His Pleaſure muſt go on, however our private Intereſts are diſordered by it: In a common Flame particular Hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes muſt ſuffer blowing up, and leſſer Buildings give way, and make room for public princely Structures: ſometimes our Deſires, and Conveniencies are taken in, as of late; ſometimes left out; but the <hi>Myſtery of God</hi> in the <hi>Kingdom of Chriſt</hi> by the <hi>Oath of the Angel,</hi> muſt be finiſhed; there is but a ſhort Time, in compariſon now, till the <hi>Seventh Trumpet</hi> begin to <hi>finiſh</hi> it, and <hi>Time</hi> of the preſent date, of the preſent Style ſhall be no more; as He hath <hi>ſpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken by his Servants the Prophets.</hi> That Kingdom of Chriſt is, and ſhall ſuddenly appear to be the <hi>Grand Public,</hi> not only of our <hi>Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion</hi> but of the <hi>World.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And the <hi>Deſtruction</hi> of the <hi>Papacy,</hi> and the <hi>Hatred of the Whore</hi> by the <hi>Ten Kings</hi> muſt be to us, even to us, whoever we are, whether we will or no; both as to our <hi>National Intereſts,</hi> and as to our <hi>Eternal Concernments.</hi> Our <hi>National Intereſts</hi> ſhall be car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried that way, if we are moved with that <hi>Spirit of God</hi> now about to ſhew it ſelf in the World, according to our deſires; if not be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yond all our Deſires and Intendments. And as to <hi>Our Everlaſting Concernments,</hi> It is much to us, for It brings on that <hi>Day,</hi> that ſhall be either the <hi>day</hi> of <hi>our Redemption,</hi> or that ſhall <hi>burn as an Oven,</hi> and All the <hi>Wicked</hi> ſhall be <hi>conſumed</hi> in it.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Infer. </seg>2</label> Let us earneſtly pray, and wait for that <hi>Philadelphian State</hi> of the <hi>Church,</hi> that is ſo near us, and that ſhall far exceed all our preſent <hi>Church ſtates,</hi> how excellent ſoever they may be; Then ſhall the Great Truths of <hi>Goſpel-Redemption,</hi> and particular<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly the <hi>Propheſies</hi> be <hi>Sung,</hi> as a <hi>New Song,</hi> as by a Choir of <hi>Angels,</hi> the Muſick of the Spheres, and all the Servants of Chriſt under the <hi>Lamb ſtanding on Mount Zion,</hi> with his <hi>Fathers Name on their Fore-heads,</hi> ſhall <hi>learn</hi> it. And then, as by a new <hi>Miſſion,</hi> ſpeedy, and Univerſal, like the Firſt <hi>Apoſtolical Preaching,</hi> and as from the <hi>Mid-Heaven</hi> ſhall the <hi>Everlaſting Goſpel</hi> be <hi>preached</hi> to <hi>All;</hi> The disbelieved <hi>Hour of Chriſts Judgment. viz.</hi> Of his <hi>Kingdom</hi> or <hi>Government,</hi> that begins with a <hi>Judiciary Proceſs,</hi> ſhall be <hi>Thun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der'd</hi> out, as nigh, to <hi>All Nations.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The <hi>Fall of Babylon,</hi> and the Judgment on the <hi>Beaſts Worſhip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers</hi> ſhall be declared with a New Majeſty and Power. The <hi>Firſt Reſurrection (Bleſſed are the Dead,</hi> &amp;c.) ſhall be promulg'd; Pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:59786:14"/> for the Converſion of the <hi>Fulneſs of the Gentiles,</hi> and ſo of the <hi>Jews</hi> ſhall be <hi>anſwered</hi> by Chriſt with the <hi>Crown on his Head,</hi> and the <hi>ſharp Sickle</hi> in his Hand, <hi>reaping the Harveſt of the Earth,</hi> as Ripe for the <hi>Salvation</hi> of all <hi>Iſrael;</hi> and then is the <hi>Vine of the Earth gathered,</hi> eſpecially the <hi>Cluſters of Spiritual Sodom,</hi> and thrown into the <hi>Wine-preſs</hi> of the <hi>Wrath of God,</hi> and from <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hence the <hi>Vials</hi> are <hi>fill'd</hi> and <hi>pour'd out in Judgment.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Then the <hi>Opened Temple</hi> ſhall ſhew the <hi>Tabernacle</hi> of <hi>Teſtimony,</hi> and the <hi>Ark of the Teſtament,</hi> and be <hi>filled with Smoke,</hi> becauſe the <hi>Divine Glory</hi> is coming to <hi>dwell</hi> there; that is, <hi>Ezekiels Temple,</hi> and <hi>City,</hi> and the <hi>New Jeruſalem</hi> of the <hi>Apoſtle John</hi> ſhall be <hi>ſpiritual<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>z'd</hi> into one <hi>Divine Preſence</hi> of <hi>God,</hi> and of the <hi>Lamb,</hi> which is the <hi>Sanctuary cleans'd</hi> at the End of <hi>Daniels</hi> 2300 Ev. Morn.</p>
               <p>Theſe Things God will be <hi>Enquir'd of</hi> for, by the Prayers of his <hi>Servants</hi> awakned thereunto. But they are by the <hi>demand</hi> of the <hi>Watchers,</hi> and by the <hi>Word</hi> of the <hi>Holy,</hi> however light they are made of; and therefore ſhall certainly be in their Seaſon.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Infer. </seg>3</label> We are hereby made to underſtand, how to pray for the <hi>Powers,</hi> that are <hi>ſet over us by God,</hi> as in Relation to the moſt Supreme part of their <hi>Adminiſtration. As now for the King,</hi> the on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Prayer, that can be made for him in <hi>Faith,</hi> with reſpect to the <hi>Regal Power,</hi> is, that He may be one of thoſe, that may <hi>hate the Whore;</hi> elſe in a <hi>Proteſtant Nation,</hi> reſcued from the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> and the <hi>Whore, Prophecy</hi> will not allow him at this Time, I do not ſay, of the <hi>Day,</hi> but of the <hi>Beaſts laſt Moon,</hi> though it be indeed alſo the <hi>Half day,</hi> ſince the <hi>Reformation;</hi> had it not been for this Prophecy, there had not been ſuch an eaſie Retirement of Him from <hi>Government.</hi> An <hi>Atheiſt</hi> may ſee, and the greateſt <hi>Infidel</hi> in <hi>Sacred Prophecy</hi> be convinc'd.</p>
               <p>The Great Prayer for the <hi>Proteſtant Prince,</hi> whom God hath <hi>ſtirred</hi> up to be a <hi>Deliverer,</hi> is, That He may be a <hi>poliſhed Shaft</hi> in <hi>Gods Quiver,</hi> and that God would <hi>fill</hi> his <hi>Bow with Him,</hi> and make Him as the <hi>Sword of a mighty man,</hi> that he may <hi>ride out proſperouſly</hi> and atchieve High in this Great work, that is to be done, that after the <hi>overthrow of the Throne of Kingdoms,</hi> and of the <hi>Rider,</hi> &amp;c. He would make him a <hi>Signet,</hi> as having <hi>choſen Him;</hi> And for the <hi>aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembled Councels</hi> of the <hi>Nation,</hi> that they may be with the <hi>Lamb,</hi> who is appearing <hi>King of Kings,</hi> and <hi>Lord of Lords,</hi> as His <hi>Called, Faithful,</hi> and <hi>choſen,</hi> now his Victory over the <hi>Ten Kings,</hi> who have, and who yet make <hi>War</hi> with Him, is ſo near.</p>
               <p>For the <hi>Witneſſes</hi> of Chriſt in this <hi>Nation</hi> of all Kinds, our Pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er ſhould be, that they may ſo finiſh their <hi>Sack cloth Prophecy,</hi>
                  <pb n="20" facs="tcp:59786:15"/> that they may <hi>hear</hi> that <hi>Voice,</hi> Come up hither.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Infer. </seg>4</label> Let us review this ſo freſh, <hi>wonderful doing</hi> of God in this Nation, with a Wiſdom and Conſideration guided and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ducted by <hi>Prophecy;</hi> let us behold it in All the Circumſtances of it, eſpecially in this, that God hath <hi>fruſtrated the Tokens of the Babi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lonian Lyars,</hi> and made the <hi>Divinors</hi> at <hi>Loretto,</hi> and the <hi>Infallible Chair, Mad;</hi> but hath begun to <hi>perform the Counſel</hi> of his <hi>Meſſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers,</hi> ſaying to <hi>Babylon, It ſhall Fall,</hi> and to his <hi>New Jeruſalem, It ſhall be built;</hi> and to thoſe of the <hi>Ten Kings,</hi> who are now of the <hi>Reformation, You are my Shepherds, and ſhall perform my Pleaſure,</hi> till All the other of the <hi>Ten Kings</hi> alſo unite in <hi>Hating the Whore, when the words of God are fulfilled</hi> to the utmoſt.</p>
               <p>As a Pattern hereof, He hath <hi>bowed the Hearts of the People of the Nation,</hi> as <hi>one Man;</hi> He hath brought the Notions of <hi>Loy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty, Non-Reſiſtance,</hi> and <hi>Paſſive Obedience,</hi> into Subjection to <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phecy.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Infer. </seg>5</label> Let us ſeriouſly conſider, <hi>All who love the Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> and ſincerely pray, <hi>Thy Kingdom Come,</hi> according to the <hi>Prayer</hi> of the <hi>Kingdom,</hi> whether we would chooſe, and deſire, that this late <hi>Revolution</hi> ſhould be (though ſet at the higheſt Elevation) a Mercy to the <hi>Nation,</hi> and to his Servants in it upon their very Prayers, but not in order to any further great End according to that admirable <hi>Prophecy of the New Teſtament, the Revelation;</hi> or whether we would chooſe and deſire; It ſhould be for the remo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>val of that Great <hi>Remo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>a</hi> and Eſtopple of the <hi>Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> the <hi>Papacy,</hi> a Beginning of the Train of Things, that ſhall paſs ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to <hi>Prophecy</hi> in this order. <hi>viz.</hi> Begin at this <hi>Prophecy</hi> of the Text, <hi>Chap.</hi> 17. <hi>v.</hi> 16, 17. and ſet it before <hi>c.</hi> 11. 11. to the End, and ſo paſs to <hi>c:</hi> 14. and carry a line through it, to <hi>c.</hi> 15. <hi>c.</hi> 16. <hi>c.</hi> 18. <hi>c.</hi> 19. <hi>c.</hi> 20. <hi>c.</hi> 21. <hi>c.</hi> 22. to <hi>v.</hi> For ſo I am aſſured, God hath begun in <hi>our Nation,</hi> ſo, as He will extend this Prophe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tical Line through the World, reaching to that Glorious <hi>Jeru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſalem.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>According to our deſire herein, let us ſearch that <hi>Prophecy,</hi> and <hi>ſet our Faces</hi> to the <hi>Lord our God</hi> by <hi>Prayer</hi> and <hi>Supplication,</hi> with <hi>Faſting, Sack cloth,</hi> and <hi>Aſhes:</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Infer. </seg>6</label> The <hi>Philadelphian</hi> State of the <hi>Church,</hi> that ſhall be at the End of the <hi>Apoſtaſie,</hi> is the Exemplar or Pattern, at which All the <hi>Proteſtant Churches</hi> ſhould aim, as being indeed the <hi>Reſt,</hi> or<note place="margin">Rev. 3. 2. <gap reason="foreign">
                        <desc>〈 in non-Latin alphabet 〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </note> 
                  <hi>Remainders</hi> that are to fill up the <hi>Reformation,</hi> upon which the <hi>New Jeruſalem</hi> ſhall <hi>come down,</hi> in which the <hi>Sanctuary cleanſed</hi> appears. This we ſhould aim at in <hi>Brotherly Love,</hi> imported in its
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:59786:15"/> very Name, which is the <hi>Bands</hi> and the <hi>Beauty</hi> of that <hi>Church;</hi> In <hi>Holding faſt the Name of Chriſt</hi> in his Supreme <hi>Paſtoral</hi> and <hi>Epiſcopal</hi> Office, receiving nothing, but from his <hi>Voice,</hi> entring by the <hi>Door</hi> of his ſole <hi>Authority,</hi> and <hi>flying from the Voice of Strangers;</hi> in keeping the <hi>Word of his Patience,</hi> or ſtaying for the <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nfading Crown</hi> until his <hi>Glorious Kingdom;</hi> in <hi>looking</hi> for, and <hi>haſting</hi> to it. For in too great an <hi>Ignorance,</hi> and <hi>unbelief</hi> of it, the very <hi>wiſe Vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gins</hi> of the <hi>Proteſtant Churches</hi> are <hi>ſlumbring</hi> and <hi>ſleeping</hi> at this Day.</p>
               <p>In laying aſide all Auſtere <hi>Ceremonialneſs</hi> out of over-Reverence to <hi>Antiquity;</hi> and rather <hi>humbling</hi> our ſelves and acknowledging an Error in too near Approaches to that <hi>Synagogue</hi> of <hi>Sathan,</hi> that ſhew'd it ſelf before the laſt of thoſe <hi>Four firſt General Councels:</hi> Laſtly, in a Great Moderation of Cenſure towards thoſe <hi>Churches,</hi> and <hi>Proteſtants,</hi> who were ſo greatly miſtaken in that laſt point; not Reproaching them as <hi>Antichriſtian,</hi> or having ſo much as the <hi>number</hi> of that unhappy <hi>Name;</hi> however too near approaching the <hi>Ritual</hi> and <hi>High Juriſdictive Synagogue,</hi> that led to it at firſt. But now ſuch ſhall ſee their Fault by the Inſtruction of <hi>Chriſt Him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf,</hi> who Receives, and owns them: and thus ſhould we All joyn in ſeeking the <hi>Beloved</hi> of the <hi>Church</hi> together, till He appear on the <hi>Mountain of Spices.</hi> Cantic. 6. 1. c. 8. laſt.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="postscript">
            <head>POSTSCRIPT.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>JEremiah,</hi> when He had <hi>Writ</hi> All the <hi>Words</hi> concerning <hi>Babylon</hi> in a <hi>Book,</hi> gave it to <hi>Serajah</hi> a <hi>Quiet Prince</hi> to <hi>Read,</hi> when He<note place="margin">Jerem. 51. 59.</note> 
               <hi>Came to Babylon,</hi> and to <hi>pray</hi> according to it; and then to <hi>bind</hi> it to a <hi>Stone,</hi> and to <hi>ſink</hi> it to the <hi>bottom</hi> of <hi>Euphrates,</hi> as a <hi>Symbol</hi> of the then <hi>Babylon ſinking,</hi> and to <hi>Riſe</hi> no <hi>more:</hi> yet <hi>Jeremiahs Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſie</hi> Roſe again when <hi>Babylon Fell,</hi> as is particularly Remark'd, 2 <hi>Chron.</hi> 36. 22.</p>
            <p>Now I offer theſe Words of <hi>Myſtical Babylon Sinking,</hi> to every <hi>Quiet, Calm, Sedate Mind;</hi> I only requeſt ſuch to obſerve, how <hi>Providence</hi> moves, and goes on according to the <hi>Propheſie</hi> expound<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in them, while It is yet ſtanding.</p>
            <pb n="22" facs="tcp:59786:16" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p> Let the Diſcourſes, and the Inſtrument, us'd by God, (how<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever unworthy) ſink to the Loweſt; It may very well be ſo; yet l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>t none be <hi>Scandalized;</hi> even that ſhall be only a <hi>Symbol</hi> of the <hi>Babylon,</hi> that now is, <hi>ſinking;</hi> Theſe very Diſcourſes ſhall Riſe into particular Remembrance, when <hi>Babylon Falls.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I do not pretend to particular <hi>Inſpiration;</hi> but the Obſervation of the cloſe Chain, and curious Links of <hi>Prophetical Scripture,</hi> ſince the World began, requires ſo intent, and nice a <hi>Speculation,</hi> that the Diſcovery is almoſt as particular, as <hi>Inſpiration;</hi> and when they are found, they are ſo even, juſt, ſolid, ſubſtantial, that I doubt not to ſay, They are certain, as <hi>Inſpiration,</hi> For <hi>V<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſion</hi> or <hi>Prophecy</hi> cannot <hi>Lye:</hi> And there may be ſuch a Manifeſtation of the <hi>Comm<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſſures</hi> and admirable Connexions of one part with ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, that ſooner may the moſt exact <hi>Anatomiſts</hi> be deceiv'd in their Eye-ſight, though aſſiſted with <hi>Microſcopes,</hi> and utmoſt Art, and in their Reaſon and Admiration of the <hi>Works of God</hi> in Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, upon their Eye-ſight, then thoſe Nerves and Fibres of <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phetical Scripture</hi> deceive: They are ſuch and ſo laid, that no Fancy could create them; This is my Aſſurance.</p>
            <p>Yet even a <hi>Prophet</hi> muſt not look for <hi>Honour,</hi> or <hi>Acceptance</hi> more in his <hi>own Time,</hi> then in his <hi>own Country;</hi> His <hi>Words coming to paſs</hi> are the <hi>Credential,</hi> Moſt require, that <hi>God hath ſent him. The Jews built not the Sepulchres</hi> of the <hi>Prophets, whom their Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers killed,</hi> till they knew their <hi>Words had come to paſs.</hi> It muſt much more fare ſo with the Expoſitors of <hi>Prophecy,</hi> but concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing that, <hi>The Will of the Lord be done.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I only beg the Favour of ſuch Aſſiſtance, as that the whole Work may be perfected, and laid up for the Time to come; and propoſe Thirty Sheets yet to be printed, and deſire Two Shillings ſix pence of each Aſſiſtant, to carry on the Impreſſion.</p>
            <p>[Parts Printed.] <hi>The Scripture Line of Time, from the firſt Sab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bath to</hi> Abraham; <hi>from</hi> Cyrus <hi>to the Milennial Sabbatiſm. The Song of</hi> Solomon <hi>adjuſted from</hi> Davids <hi>Kingdom to the Kingdom of the Root and Off-ſpring of</hi> David, <hi>Jeſus Chriſt. The Command to Come out of</hi> Babylon, <hi>w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>th this Treatiſe in Appendage.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>[To be Printed.] <hi>The Scripture Line from</hi> Abraham <hi>to</hi> Cyrus. <hi>The Goſpel Doctrine of the Kingdom. The Prayer of the Kingdom, or the Lords Prayer; The Sacrament of the Kingdom, or the Lords Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per; Adjuſted to that Kingdom.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
